One!
一!
Three the eyes!
看準目標!
Two!
二!
Between the eyes
正對眉心!
Out!
出界!
What?!
什麼?!
- She's safe. - She was out.
- 她在界內 - 她在界外
She landed right there, she's safe.
她明明就摔在那,是界內!
Ah, come on. That's enough, I don't wanna hear another word.
行了,夠了,我不想再多聽一句狡辯！
- Foul OUT! - Calm Down.
- 罰出場! - 別那麼激動
My grandmother just takes me to the Wash Square Park.
有次我奶奶帶我去沃什廣場公園玩
I watched Bobby Fischer played ten games at the same time.
我正好看到博比·菲捨爾同時 進行十桌比賽
Queen me
讓我驚詫
He made five, six moves ahead on each table.
他每桌棋都能算多五,六步
Anyway, he became World Champ, Didn't he?
總之，他後來成了世界冠軍，不是麼
Then lost his fucking mind.
然而他卻開始精神錯亂了
Became a revin paranoid, being attacked on more direction.
成了妄想狂，受到各界人士的攻擊
He couldn't see a reason for them.
而他自己卻不知道為什麼
Mate!
絕殺！
My name is David Fisk.
我叫大衛·費斯克
Detective 1st Grade I've been a cop in NYPD for over 30 years.
一級警官 在紐約警署已工作30多年
in that time
在這期間
I've killed fourteen people.
我一共殺了14個人
Relive that one more time.
重放一遍
He's nuts.
真是個變態
When these things started...
這是從什麼時候開始的…
How did they start...
怎麼開始的…
Maybe this one started with this guy named Charles Randall.
或許是從這個叫查爾斯·蘭德爾 的傢伙開始的
Randall was a child killer.
蘭德爾是個孩童謀殺犯
He killed his girlfriend's daughter about four years ago.
四年前他殺死了他女友的女兒
AssHole.
放了我，媽的
He was tried for his crime but was acquited by jury for his spouse.
他受到了指控，但卻因為證據不足 被陪審團無罪釋放
My partner and I found this unacceptable.
我和我的搭檔都無法接受這個結果
My partner is a good man.
我的搭檔是個好人
Are you really going to do this thing?
你真的打算這麼幹？
Do what?
怎麼幹？
You're gonna take down Randall.
你想陷害蘭德爾
For home society he didn't commit.
用無證持槍罪陷害他
What am I gonna do?
我能怎麼辦？
You are my partner.
你可是我的搭檔
You are my role model.
你還是我的楷模
- Right. - What am I gonna do without role model?
- 沒錯 - 沒了楷模我該怎麼辦？
We didn't have this conversation.
今天的對話沒發生過
What conversation.
什麼對話
I got it done.
我把事情解決了
Randall lost his freedom.
蘭德爾沒了自由
For the crime he didn't commit.
是因為他並沒犯下的罪
I lost my faith.
我則沒了信仰
- I wanna go. - OK
- 我想走了 - OK
You can take this as a confession, if you want.
如果你願意 你可以把這當做是懺悔
Whatever.
什麼都行
A few weeks ago, things heated up.
幾周前，事情升溫了
What we got on them, Turk?
咱們掌握了哪些資料，頑童?
Mark Smith, As Known As "Spider" big drug dealer, murders, extortion, lots of nice things.
馬克·史密斯, 人稱"蜘蛛" 毒品走私，殺人放火，敲詐勒索，全是美差
Converted this old Banner Bank to a Club 404 Harlem.
他把這間老Banner銀行改成了 黑人404夜總會
Maybe when he sees us so confess.
或許他見了咱們就坦白罪行了
What, You don't believe the miracles?
怎麼，你不相信奇跡啊？
You picked up a check one day, one day, then I blelieve the miracles.
如果你哪次能撿到一張支票，就一次 那我就相信奇跡了
- Let's go, I'm buying. - Yeah, that's the miracle I want some.
- 走吧，我請客 - 對嘍，這是我想要的奇跡
- This is where he launder his money. - Oh yeah. Cleaning, Clean, Clean.
- 這就是他洗錢的地方 - 噢，耶，洗啊，洗啊，洗！
Clean all his mess.
洗掉他所有的垃圾
I gotta take a leak.
我要去解手
I'll just be in a sec, I'm not peeking.
我就呆一會，我可沒偷看
No problem.
沒事
You guys are so lucky.
你們男人可真幸運
What is that?
怎麼說？
No line to the bathroom, and...
不用排對上廁所，而且…
You guys pee standing up.
你們站著就能撒尿
And zip, ..., zip... by the boom by the wing get out here.
拉開鏈，拉上鏈 三下五除二，就完事走人了
The big I really deal with myself on this thing.
嗯，這話我倒是不得不承認
You want a bump?
想來點嗎？
Where's your that from?
哪來的？
Spider, it's prima.
蜘蛛，上品哦
Not bad.
不賴嘛
Not bad?
不賴？
What fuck are you looking for?
你想還要什麼樣的？
Come on, Turk, you pulled my hair.
拜託，頑童，你還拽我頭髮
My little sister used to pull my hair harder than that.
我的小妹妹以前 拽我頭髮都比你的有勁
Whatever.
隨便你了
I gotta go.
我得走了
Where the fuck you going?
你他媽往哪跑呢？
I'm going to retire.
我要退出！
Ritire?
退出？
This is America. You winy bitch.
這是在美國！你個醉婊子！
You just fucking get into the cab, and on your work.
你他媽老老實實上車 然後去幹活
Yeah, she's on the way. She cann't wait to see you.
是的，她在路上了 她都等不及了
Rambo this skate boy pimp is my tenth kill.
蘭博這個皮條滑板男 是我殺的第十人
Taking me as a street sweeper.
你可以把我當做清道夫
I cleaned up this worthless piece of shit and left him an obituary sols.
我把這個一文不值的渣碎清掉 還留下了一首訃文
It rhymes.
還是押韻的
Rooster, we're gonna find out who did this.
風凰，我們得找出是誰幹的
Give him a medal.
送他一塊獎牌
Hey, Rambo, see who will do this?
嘿，小子，誰會殺你？
He ain't talk, aint he?
他沒法開口，是不是？
- Real name, Robert Bridie
真名，羅伯特·布萊迪
Robert Bridie, Damn shame.
羅伯特·布萊迪，真想不到
What're you thinking? Mash?Gray?
你在想什麼？ 瑪什？格雷？
You guys wanna mess my crime scene again?
你們兩個是不是 又想搞亂罪犯現場？
You don't who Bobby Bridie is ?
你不知道誰是羅伯特·布萊迪？
I have met him an hour ago.
一小時前剛見過
It looks like close french.
看起來射擊範圍很近
Yeah, from the stippling on the wound, that's two three feet away.
是的，從傷口的測量來估計 大約在二、三尺外
There will be fish and flagon out of his brains.
腦袋都能打開花了
- What? - Well, I just got that.
- 怎麼了？ - 我剛剛學到的
Mash Gray
瑪什·格雷
Good one, Rooster.
不錯嘛，風凰
That's quick.
學的挺快
I just tried to keep pace with you.
只是跟上你的步伐而已
HE TRADES IN SIN DISTRIBUTE FLESH
「他帶著罪孽 做著靈與肉的買賣「
HE PICKS THE FRUIT WHEN IT IS FRESH
「誘人的鮮果 是他的最愛」
NOW SOMEONE ELSE MUST SLAP HIS WHORE
「必須有人喚醒他的娼妓」
HIS HEART HAS STOPPED, HE BREATH NO MORE.
「他沒了心跳 也停止了呼吸」
What do you wanna do about this?
這個你有什麼看法？
I say let's make the best activity.
我有個最好的方法
Canvas the whores, 'cause maybe you will meet one you like.
徹底盤查所有妓女 因為說不定你能碰到合適的
Na, Please. I got one to handle from you know who.
算了，你又不是不知道 那一個我已經夠受的了
Don't shade.
別不好意思嘛
She's gotten my phallus level slow, so I gotta sit down to take a piece.
她總是搞的我挺不久 所以我得經常停下來歇一歇
- Oh, thank you for that picture. - He, what can I tell you.
- 噢，真多謝你的表述 - 嘿，我能說什麼呢
How can I help you, Gentleman?
有什麼要幫忙的嗎，先生們？
We would like to talk about your boss.
我們想跟你談談你的老闆
He's upstairs.
他就在樓上
Your other boss.
另一個老闆
Rambo...
蘭博...
He's asshole.
他是個混蛋
Why he's asshole?
為什麼他是混蛋？
Follow me, please.
請跟我來
You know anybody..., wanna kill him?
你知道誰…，想要殺他嗎？
Me.
我
Anyone else?
還有別人嗎？
Why?
怎麼了？
He's dead?
他死了？
Hey, Listen, you wanna smart and help us out, or I'm gonna call somebody in ICE...
嘿，聽著，你最好乖乖跟我們合作 不然我就找出入境處的人來…
and have you explain to pass the land.
到時你得好好想想 怎麼回老家了
Go ahead, I'm an American citizen.
隨便，我是美國公民
You can lick my ball anytime.
隨時歡迎你來給我吹簫
What?
什麼？
Call us anytime, you know... if you hear something, anything.
如果你聽到什麼風聲的話 隨時可以聯繫我們
I think we are looking for a guy named Sam the Butcher out.
我看我們是在找一個叫 「山姆屠夫請你出來」的人
Who?
誰？
Nice kidding around.
他在開玩笑
But seriously, Lieutenant, how far you want us to go with this Rambo murder?
不過說真的，長官，關於這個蘭博案子 你到底想讓我們查多久？
I don't know, I think maybe you investigate a little more, figure out who did it...
我也不知道，或許你們該加把勁 找出誰是兇手…
...try to put him into jail.
把他關進大牢
As it doesn't get in the way of your shuffle board lessons.
免得它讓你上不了 "沙壺球"的課
Yeah, No problem.
行，沒問題
We are also working on this dealer "Spider" as tight as two steps to find out the fresh kills.
我們還在查「蜘蛛」 已經查到最近兩起兇殺案跟他有關
We can near him, who knows how far of the lie riddle lead.
我們有辦法接近他 有個線人能從他那拿到貨
So what about it?
怎麼個情況？
I poped a slit would annouce a blow, she just showed up by nose.
我在尿尿的時候 她剛好在那嗑藥
I got the flip on him.
而她剛好跟「蜘蛛」有聯繫
Lucky fuck, ah?
狗屎運，哈？
- So she got it from him directly? - Yeah, she did.
- 這麼說她直接從他那拿貨？ - 是的，沒錯
Good.
很好
OK, We get a way he cann't hang on, then kick a loose.
OK，找個方法讓他上套 把事了了
I hate trying to prosecute fucking laze.
整天想法起訴這些鳥人 我都煩透了
This isn't Spider Club.
這不是「蜘蛛」的夜總會啊？
Backyard.
是後院
Yeah, it's an abandoned linen Factory, Jessica
沒錯，這原本是個 廢棄的針線廠， 傑西卡
I guess I'm at your role of... What you call it?
我猜我現在就算… 你們叫什麼來著？
- Rat. - Stoolie.
- 線人 - 臥底
Thanks.
謝謝
I mean I think usually some poor African-American caters, junk here, or prostitute.
我是說通常這裡都是一些 非洲裔的美國人，吸毒者，或者妓女什麼的
There was a long way 200 and many years the club boys...
200多年來，這些夜總會仔…
...were smarter than the African and American junky whore.
確實是覺得他們比那些 非洲裔的吸毒的妓女聰明
Normally, but sometimes they only think they are.
總的來說是這樣 不過有時只是他們自以為是
It's all settled, Sir.
都安排妥了，長官
You guys are sure safe in there?
你們確定裡面安全嗎？
Tell your girlfriend to grow up here. And let's go.
告訴你的朋友別擔心 可以出發了
What do you say, Counsellor? Ready to do this thing?
怎麼樣，大律師？準備好了嗎？
Yeah, let's get over with it.
是的，咱們開始吧
OK, when all we set, you go in there, you wait him for asking you for what you need.
OK，等我們安排完了，你就進去 等他主動問你
And you don't come back here with less than four ounces.
但是，少於4盎司的話 我們可不答應
- Four aounces? - Yeah.
- 4盎司？ - 是的
Isn't that a lot? I just buy a little bit and that's it.
那是不是太多了？ 平時我只買一點，夠用就行
Just say you're gonna ski for weeks with fresh powder.
你可以說你要去滑雪 要用幾周的白粉
Yeah, you tell him you are going on vacation.
對啊，你跟他說你要去度假嘛
I do this thing and my records wiped clean.
我幫你們這事 然後我的不良記錄全部清空
As a whistle.
一乾二淨
No one in that loft room and then I got busted, right?
如果那裡沒人的話 我還是要被抓去做牢，是不是？
That never happened.
沒那樣的事！
Counsellor, we all know you better than this.
大律師，我們知道你可以做得更好
You just do this, you stop showing off and shut up your nose, you go home...
你只要按計劃行事，然後你就可以退出了 沒人會煩你，你可以回家…
You got married, you got kids, you never come back again, and that's that.
結婚，生子，永遠不用回來 多美好
Yeah.
是啊
Okay, we're going.
OK，出發了
Yes, sir!
是，長官！
Hey, Jessica.
嘿, 傑西卡.
Beak a leg.
祝你好運
Two flats down, door is on the left, ring the bell.
下去兩層，門在左手邊 到了按鈴
Hey, Stubby, why don't you just go down get our company up here?
嘿，矬子，下去把客人接上來
Come on, fat boy.
快點，肥仔
Get it on.
好戲上演
Good afternoon, Ya.
下午好
Hey, Spider.
嘿，蜘蛛
- I'll be on the stairs. - All right.
- 我在樓梯看著 - 好的
- How are you? - I'm fine, baby.
- 怎麼樣？ - 很好，寶貝
Checking out this video sheet before my kids watching it. Have you seen this?
正在幫我的小孩審片 你看過這個沒？
No.
還沒
'Cause you just don't deal with them, let them alone they stir to that junkie.
你沒小孩是用不著 如果讓他們胡來，很容易變成癮君子了
You know what I'm saying?
懂我的意思嗎？
You know, he's gotten the point.
知道麼，他說對了
- Remember Underdog? - What dog?
- 記得「超人狗」嗎？ - 什麼狗？
That fucking dog, spawn a generation of junkies.
就他媽那支狗啊 搞的一代人都成了癮君子的狗
So you converted the bank into a club and recording studio?
這麼說你把這個銀行 變成了你的夜總會和錄音棚？
- Yeah, do you like it? - Yeah.
- 是啊，怎麼樣？ - 不錯
What are you talking about?
你說什麼呢？
What did the underdog do all the time?
「超人狗」平時都幹什麼？
It was shining shoes,
沒事的時候他擦鞋
and when Sweet Polly Purebred called out to him, his dog's ears will pick it up and he will rescue her.
如果小甜心波莉·阿純向他求救 他的耳朵總能聽到，然後就飛去救她
And what's he doing when he needs super strength? He goes to his ring, remember?
然後他需要超能力的時候怎麼辦？ 他要找他的鈴鐺，記得嗎？
Pull out a pill, pop it.
拿出一個藥片，吞了它
Holly shit, you are right.
噢，哎呀，你說的對
He was a little fucking speak for you.
他還真像你說的那樣
So what's the business?
這次要多少？
How about QP?
給多少我要多少
I think it good for QP.
我考慮多拿點
Fuck how long with QP?
要那麼多干他媽嘛？
I'm gonna ski, with friends.
我要去滑雪，跟朋友一起
A lot of friends.
很多朋友
Where?
在哪？
Aspen, Colorado.
阿斯蓬，科羅拉多
Shit, I'll show you some you're going ask us.
我帶你看看 你準備要買的東西
Now you prima grand.
肯定是上品了
- Whisky? - Sure, my whole life.
- 威士忌？ - 當然，我的最愛
Come on, I mean I don't have all day.
我是說有機會的時候 我都會選威士忌
I want you to put off that jacket, be still a little while.
我想讓你把夾克脫了 涼快涼快
What do you think?
你怎麼看？
Actually, I gotta run. I have major IPO closing in one hour, so...
是這樣的，我馬上就得走 一小時後我得參加一個募股的閉幕式
That is just to scare you, let you know.
我只是想嚇嚇你 讓你知道而已
Absolutely I get...
是，很明顯我知道了
What do you want to do?
你有什麼打算？
You know where you hide the wire?
你知道在哪藏竅聽器嗎？
well you've been such a bitch, you pop chose a wrong nigger like me.
你個臭婊子，想騙像我這樣的黑鬼？ 我看你是選錯人了！
You're scared, now.
現在你怕了，啊？
Looks like your cowboy coming to rescue you.
看來你的帥哥們來救你了
Can I help you, Gentlemen?
請問有什麼事，先生們？
Yeah, let us in, Spider.
讓我們進去，蜘蛛
I'm sorry, but there's no one here by that name.
對不起，這沒有叫那個名子的人
- Let us in - We only wanna talk to you.
- 讓我們進去 - 我們只想跟你談談
See, I know how to look,
看著，我知道怎麼找
and I know where to look.
我也知道在哪找
Come to Papa.
來爸爸這
It always hurts for the firt time.
第一次總是很疼的
Are you all right?
你沒事吧？
Why would she be aid, she's watching TV.
為什麼你們跑來救她？ 她只不過是在看電視
As fuck as she got hurt for watching TV.
除非看電視也能他媽的受傷
- She could have seen, I heard,  something scared her. - Like what?
- 她可能見到了嚇人的東西，我聽到了 - 比如說？
Like some big fuck machoist big fat fucking mouth dog.
比如說 張著他媽的大嘴巴狂吠的公瘋狗
Well, nobody here fits that description till a minute ago.
是麼，這裡一分鐘前可沒那樣的動物
I'm gonna show you, ugly fuck...
我要讓你看看，你媽的…
- We said enough. - If then, bring your wife up here.
- 咱們說夠了 - 如果那樣，你得把你老婆帶來了
That's enough, let's go, let's go. It's okay.
夠了夠了，咱們走，咱們走 沒事了
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm okay.
- 你沒事嗎？ - 是的，我沒事
- I'm okay. - You want your wire back?
- 我沒事 - 想要回你的竊聽器？
Fire!
有槍！
No, Stubby, No!
不要，矬子，不要！
Get down! Get the fuck down!
趴下！給我他媽趴下！
Come on!
快點！
Fat one is dead.
肥的那個死了
That went well?
這下好了…
Oh, shit, you're bleeding.
噢，天，你流血了
3-4 squad to central 1141 request ambulance.
3-4分隊呼叫總部 11-41請求救護車
I need the EMS(Emergency Medical Services), subject shot at 184 St. Niklaas.
我需要緊急醫療救助 有人中槍，地點在聖·尼克拉斯184號
- I've tried the best that I can... - You're gonna be just fine, Concy, just fine.
- 我已經盡力了… - 你會沒事的，沒事的
Just relax.
放鬆
Hey, guys, if you ever need a lawyer...
嘿，夥計們 如果你們要找律師的話…
In good old days,
要是在過去
we left the criminal sleep down before call for the ambulance.
我們會讓罪犯斷了氣 才去叫救護車
- Calm, calm, ... - Fucking lowlife.
- 冷靜，冷靜 - 他媽的垃圾
Made your point, you made your point.
你說的對，你說的對
Tough a little bit, ain't you? Kick me when I'm handcuffed.
裝牛了，是不？ 踢一個被銬上的我
Shut your fuck up, you piece of shit!
閉他媽的嘴，你這坨屎！
You think I won't blow your fucking head off?
你以為我不敢開槍打你？
I wouldn't think twice about it.
我連想都不用想！
I go in there, get the fat boy's gun. Come back to you.
我進去，拿起肥仔的槍 回來你這
Between your eyes.
正中眉心
Where's EMS?
救護車在哪？
This thing was a cluster fucked and all cluster fucks.
這事糟透了 而且糟到家了
You got nothing.
你們什麼都沒弄到
What about finding the murder?
算是查到兇手怎麼樣？
No drugs, right? So..., No preaddict felon and No conspiracy, No nothing.
沒有毒品，是吧？所以… 沒有重犯，沒有共犯，什麼都沒有
No felon, no felon, I can't believe just no felon, how do you spell felon.
沒重犯，沒重犯，真他媽不明白 就一句沒重犯！你知道怎麼寫「重犯」！
Harlem site, racketeer, drugs. I mean what are we talking about?
黑人區，詐騙犯，毒品 我是說我們到底在說什麼！？
Hey, you are lucky that white girl didn't die!
嘿，你該燒高香了 幸虧那個女孩沒死！
IAB is gonna interview both of you and do a preliminary report over the next couple of weeks.
IAB會盤問你們兩個 接下來幾周你們兩個好好準備一下
Now, off the record... You actually didn't violate the procedure.
私底下說一句 還算是你們沒壞了程序
Because the victim had a firearm and did you.
因為是死者先開的槍 然後才是你們
So if you stick together, you should make through this.
所以如果你們兩個通好氣 應該沒問題
You better get your story straight, dude.
最好別撒謊，你們兩個
Because I'm not going back to Far Rockway, because you two fucked up.
因為我沒法回「法羅克維」 全拜你們兩個所賜
And you gonna spend some couch time with Rubber Gun Squad.
你們還得跟「橡膠槍」小隊一樣 體會一下「心理醫療」
You better take this shrink seriously. Or you will be all out of duty.
最好把這個心理醫生當回事 不然你們就要被解職了
That fucking piece of shit just walks.
那個他媽的鳥人 就那麼大搖大擺的走了
Knock it off, Turk!
別再提了，頑童！
Relax, partner, he's gonna get gears.
放鬆點，搭檔，事情會解決的
Gentlemen,
先生們
your questions.
請問問題
Who made the decision to enter at that time.
當時誰做的決定？
I did.
我做的
- Whoes decision was at the end of this crisis? - Mine.
- 最後關頭誰下的決定？ - 我
- Did you immediately identify yourselves as police offiers? - Yes, we did.
- 你們有沒有即時表明身份？ - 是的，我們表明了
Did you immediately identify yourselves as police offiers?
你們當時立刻 表明身份了嗎？
Informer's position was becoming untellable, and we were afraid that she was in danger.
線人的處境很微妙 我們當時擔心她的安危
- Sounds like are right. - You fucking kidding note farrow.
- 好像你說的挺對 - 你他媽逗我呢啊！
- Excuse me, Detective? - Are you finishing with my client?
- 你說什麼，探長？ - 你們問完問題了嗎？
They are like Lennon and McCartney.
他們就像「列儂」和「麥卡尼特」
Not an inch lies between them.
配合的滴水不漏
What do you think?
你怎麼看？
Nothing there.
沒什麼問題
Endanger the informer, we can make them round that. They saw gun, they reacted.
危及了線人，這在情理之中 他們看到有人持槍，於是反擊了
He beat the fuckhead suspect, but he's not falling in charges.
他打了狗屁嫌疑犯 但這事對方沒起訴
Let's see what the shrink says.
看看心理醫生怎麼說吧
So, ah..., What are we gonna do now? Doc., we gonna find out define...
我們要幹嘛？ 醫生，是不是要說些…
Saying enough to carry a gun? Chase bad guys?
「拿槍拿夠了」之類的話？ 或者「抓壞人」什麼的？
OK, Why did you become a cop?
OK，你為什麼成為一名警察？
Well, it was New Year's Eve, Seems a good idea at the time.
嗯…，潮流嘛 當時這個很時髦
I don't have to say my opportunity as you had, Dr. Prosky.
我可不像您 有那麼好的機會，普羅斯基醫生
Where I come from was either gun and badge...
我生長的地方 除了槍跟警徽…
or hardhat and hammer.
就是安全帽跟錘子
How did you feel when you fired your weapon?
你開槍的時候有什麼感覺？
It's like Dirty Harry said:
就像"骯髒哈里"說的：
It's nothing wrong with a little shooting, as long as the right people get shot.
「只要你射對了人 開槍其實根本沒什麼」
When the wrong people got shot? Sucks fuck.
「而如果一旦射錯了 就全砸了」
I'd rather be end in annihilable, that's not the worst mean as you got a badge.
我倒希望能因工殉職 這樣也不算愧對我的警徽
How do you feel when you see innocent people get killed?
當你看到無辜的人被殺時 有什麼感覺？
You know....
怎麼說呢…
sort of getting numb to it.
有點麻木了
Here.
這個
I want you to take this.
我希望你拿著
Use this to jot down your thoughts, your questions, anything you may notice about yourself.
用它記下你的想法，你的問題 任何關於你的都行
Wahtever.
隨便什麼
I won't ask for it.
我不會收回來的
Just for you.
就是給你的
You should try it.
你應該試試
Sounds like a fun.
聽起來挺有趣
Go, Turk, go!
上，頑童，上啊！
You got dirt!
用足了勁！
Go!Go!
上！上！
Yeah!
耶！
Right there!
到了！
You won it!
你贏了！
Don't matter what they say about you!
別管別人怎麼說！
You're tremendous!
你就是好樣的！
Go, Turk!
衝啊，頑童！
Go!
衝啊！
Safe! You droped the ball!
界內！你掉了球了！
- What a fucking cheap shot! - That from the bat.
- 這是一個壞球！ - 那是擊球時候的事了
- Or what? Or what?... - Go after the bat.
- 不然怎麼的？不然怎麼的？ - 去跟擊球手說
Don't "or what"!
別跟我說「不然」！
I had the ball!!
我拿到球了！
The NYPD is probably more frustrations, hostility and testosterone...
紐約警署的人就是這樣 暴力，敵對，抗奮…
and ready to a rob at any moment.
隨時都可以捲入混戰
Take me as a released foul, one flicks the trigger and the pressure goes down.
我就像是出籠的猛獸，板機一扣 壓力隨之消散
You know why you enjoy the force?
你知道人為什麼喜歡暴力嗎？
To get respect!
為了得到敬畏！
Most people respect the badge.
很多人會敬畏警徽
Everybody respects the gun!
但每個人都要敬畏你的槍
Hey, Riley, I was talking to JD, you guys caught a stiff named Phillip Trager?
嘿，羅林，我聽JD說 你們發現一個死屍，叫菲利普·特雷格？
A gun runner?
走私槍支的？
- Oh, yeah, real piece of shit. - How did that go down?
- 是的，一個混球 - 怎麼死的？
I don't know. Somebody gave him a taste of his own medicine I guess.
不太清楚，我猜是有人 給他嘗了一下他自己的藥
A man intruded his apartement, killed him with one of his own guns.
那人進了他的住宅 用他販賣的槍把他斃了
The shooter, you know anything about him?
那個兇手，你們有線索嗎？
Yeah, actually the shootter left a poem.
兇手留了一首詩
He did?
真的？
Oh, shit it!
噢，真他媽的！
Simon, you ah...remember that poem?
西蒙，你還記得那首詩嗎？
The Trager case.
特雷格的案子的
- What are you doing, man? - No, Turk asked about it.
- 你幹嘛呢？ - 不是，頑童問的
What hell are you doing?
你們他媽的幹嘛呢？
Hey..., he wants to hear about the poem.
他想聽聽那首詩
YOU MUCH IN THE DEALING CLASS,
「你行如惡魔 卻自詡為神」
I SLIT HIS DOOR TO CAP THIS ASS.
「我撕開他的門 嚇破他的魂「
HE TOOK HIS GUN AND TOOK HIS...
「他拿了他的槍…」
I TOOK HIS LIFE AND TOOK HIS GUN. BUT TOO BETTER IS NOT THE ONLY ONE.
「我要了他的命，盜了他的槍」 「吾之使命卻未央」
That's all I got, something like that. It's not ain't a bit of pantoum, but it rhymes.
就這些了，差不多吧 不是什麼絕句律詩，但挺押韻
- Rooster! - Yo!
- 風凰！ - 喲！
We're looking for the same guy. He knocked off a pimp named Rambo.
我們也在找他 他把一個叫蘭博皮條客做了
A few weeks ago at Bruce Prizer. When was yours?
幾周前，在布魯斯普萊澤 你們這個是什麼時候？
Last week, we were on the roll with ATF because of the guns.
上周，當時因為盜槍的事 正在跟ATF交涉
We are back in business on the Rambo case.
我們跟到蘭博的案子了
Looks like the same guy knocked off a gun dealer on the three three last week.
看起來他把一個槍支走私犯又做了 就在上上上周
Oh, shit!
噢，真的？！
- What do you mean you are back in business? - That's our case.
- 你們說又跟上一宗案子是什麼意思？ - 這是我們的案子
You're taking our case...
你們這是撬我們的案子…
Take it along, you're learning something.
跟著我們查啦，會學到很多東西的
Tell me the guy's name is Great Grady.
是不是他叫"貪婪無極限"啊？
Please, it is, isn't it? Oh, somebody is gonna knock off the Brady Bunch.
是吧，不是嗎？ 有人要給別人找麻煩了哈
Gonna be a pouch of scrambling.
有樂子看嘍
Trager, gun runner, bites the dust Number eleven.
特雷格，倒賣槍支，見閻王了 第十一個
The bullet, matched the 45 in Trager's aparment.
這些子彈，跟特雷格住處的 45毫米口徑子彈剛好吻合
That was no surprise. So I went through ATF.
沒什麼奇怪的 所以我才找ATF
It's one of the batch of six. It's stolen from a gun shop by junior last month.
那是六份中的一份 上個月被人從槍支店裡偷了
Yeah, probably by Trager.
嗯，很可能是特雷格
That's what they think, he matches the description they have.
他們也這麼想 特雷格跟他們所掌握的資料正好相符
This still doesn't help about finding this guy,
可這對追查兇手沒什麼用
just helps the times to victims, which he's already doing a little fucking poems.
只是給死者找了條該死的罪 那傢伙還專門給這些人做詩
Hello.
你好
Hey, Turk, don't forget we got court date later.
嘿，頑童 別忘了等下還要去聽一個庭審
So, ah...
嗨…
I heard he..., ah..., shot the dealer you guys took down.
我聽說，他… 他對那個毒犯動了手
Spider.
蜘蛛？
So?
那怎麼了？
Did he?
他真的干了？
Yeah, got him down on to the ground...
是啊，把他按到地上…
the guy was handcuffed.
然後銬在桌腿上
He used to kick him when he got him.
他當時還踢了他
And then...
然後…
He gets down to the guy's chest.
他蹲下來 對著蜘蛛的胸口
And he really started. Smacked him.
他真的開始了 開始扇他
High in the face..., over and over.
重重的打在臉上 一次又一次
Screaming at the stomach and the lung. "I'm gonna break you fucking face you little bitch."
感覺他的五臟六腑都在嗷叫 「我要把你的鳥臉撕爛，你個垃圾！」
Then his eyes really started to get filled up... you know when he got...
接著他的眼睛裡就充滿了… 你知道的，當他…
"balck", you know how we get so...
「發瘋」時的樣子 你也明白我們…
rage on him.
恨透那個垃圾了
I thought he was gonna kill this guy.
我真以為他會殺了那小子的
Really?
真的？
You're a bad little girl.
你真是個壞丫頭
I gotta work to do.
我還有事做
You bad.
你真壞
Counsellor.
律師小姐
My hands are tight here, without secure Chain of Custody.
迫於目前 證據保管過程中的不當
Any evidence obtained after the initial search must be excluded.
最初現場之後收集的證據 本庭不予採納
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
他媽的開什麼玩笑
Therefore, I'm forced to grant defence motion to dismiss all charges...
所以，我不得不 撤消你們所有的指控…
of rape assault against Mr. Benlect
本萊克先生的強姦罪名不成立
Your honor.
法官大人
You think I want this guy going anywhere near my daughter?
你以為我想看著這傢伙 就這麼走出去接近我的女兒？
Or anyone's daughter for that matter?
或者任何人的女兒？
I'm unleashing your client on to the world. I'm sure we all will be back here again very soon.
我現在將你的代理人無罪釋放… 相信很快我們就會在這裡再見
Look out.
看看
Look at this motherfucker...
看看這個畜生…
Hey, a short caveat for you, come on, you're gonna get it.
嘿，給你句忠告 聽著，你最好聽清楚了
When you walk outside, watch your back.
等你走出這道門 最好留點神
Order in my court!
肅靜！庭上要肅靜！
- You mother fuck... - Not here, not now. Not here, not now.
- 你個畜生… - 這不是地方，也不是時候
Would you get him out of here, before somebody pissed nonsense on your son, and you can't be you.
你最好把他帶出去 不然有人要對你兒子發飆，你就不是你了
- Oder! Oder! - You know what I mean. Go, go.
- 肅靜！肅靜！ - 懂我的意思嗎？快，快！
Detective!
探長！
Dr. Prosky suggested that I free associated.
普羅斯基建議我做「自由聯想「
So, here I go.
所以，我有了這個：
You know what I think about when I pull a trigger?
你知道當我扣動扳機的時候 我想的是什麼嗎？
I think about the infield fly rule, I love that fucking rule.
我想的是「場內球規則」 我真是愛死這規則了
It assumes the worst of everybody.
它假定每人都有錯
It's "Sorry, batter, you're a shmuck for pop up", but the runner is on.
就像「抱歉，擊球手，你擊的爛到家了」 但跑球手已經開跑了
And you stupid ass infielder yelled "get the cheat", drop the ball, just because you called the break.
而你的場內球員卻喊著「被騙啦」 然後摔了球，就因為你叫了暫停
My favour part's the batter is out, but the runner advanced at his own risk.
我最鍾意的部分是擊球手被罰出場 而跑球手只能靠自己了
Well, isn't this a unpleasant surprise?
噢，這可真是個 不讓人驚喜的驚喜哦
That's the way I should be, you could be a motherfucker at your own risk...
我就是這樣做的 你個畜生是靠你自己…
...or not.
亦或不是呢？
Van Luytens, one less rapist. Who's gonna miss him.
范·魯特斯，少了一個強姦犯 誰會想念他？
Nobody.
沒人
Number Twelve, and counting.
第十二個，繼續
Oh,.., hot coffee.
噢，小心熱咖啡
- Morning, Detective - Morning.
- 早上好，探長 - 早上好
They are on the left.
他們在左邊
- force entry? - It doesn't look like, Dectective Perez is in there.
- 破門而入？ - 不像，佩雷斯探長已經來了
He's already there? All right
他已經來了？好的
- Hi, how about those matches last night? - Yeah, no doubt.
- 昨晚的比賽怎麼樣？ - 當然了，還用說
Hey, Teddy, Teddy, come here. Check this out.
嘿，特裡，特裡，過來 看看這個
Fuck.
我的媽
That's big.
夠大的
Powerful.
超大
- Plasma, must be? - No, CT.
- 充血，肯定是？ - 不，CT放大片
- That's plasma. - Na, it gotta be CT, look.
- 明明是充血 - 不，肯定是放大的，看
-Hey guys. - That won't be that big.
- 嘿，你們兩個 - 不然沒那麼大
Guys.
夥計們
He was shot at close range, dropped right here.
近距離中槍 橫臥在這
The pussy doesn't like him to put much of fight, doesn't it, Karen?
那雞不喜歡他用太大力 是不是，凱倫？
Nothing to indicate that.
沒看出來
Too so fast for struggle, no force entry, cuts, bruises.
太快所以沒有掙扎的跡象 沒有暴力闖入，沒有刀傷，沒有瘀傷
Hey, nobody wants to hear about your private life, officer Corelli.
嘿，沒人想聽你講你的 私生活，克萊利長官
That's a Decetive of you, Officer NeedleDick.
那是探長你 針型小雞雞長官
Looks like it's our guy again.
看來又是他
Who did he get this time?
這次他又做了誰？
It's Jon Van Luytens, owns coupla car dealer ships.
喬·范·魯特斯 擁有幾艘汽車貨輪
- Oh, shit. - He's on a rape charge, but he got tossed off last week.
- 噢，靠 - 他被控強姦，不過上周被他擺平了
Read this.
讀讀這個
THE MAN AVOID THE WAR, RESPECT FOR BEAUTY.
「他逃了兵役 卻追求美女」
CHARMER INTO OLD INTO LATE HE TOOK women...
「美女尤物，嫣紅奼紫」 「他霸了…」
...WOMEN WILL NOT GUILTY, DID NOT HAVE THE RIGHT TO LIVE.
「…霸了人家，卻以無罪自詡」 「此等惡人，謂之『該死』」
It's our boy, right?
是他，對吧？
It's got a beat for old pal Johnny.
倒是幫我們收拾了 老朋友喬尼
You know him?
你認識他？
Yeah.
是的
He was sloppy son of bitch, let me tell you.
他就一個惹人厭的畜生 如果你問我的話
You guys know how much fun it is that not catch the serial killer.
你們知道沒有抓到這個連環殺手 有多可笑嗎？
You got a point, Lieutenant?
你想說的是…，長官？
The point is...
我想說的是…
You better both think seriously about wheither or not you want to lead on this case.
你們最好想清楚了 是不是真的要帶頭查這個案子
You don't think we are up to this?
你以為我們沒盡力？
Come on.
拜託
You got what? One hundred and ten years on the job between you two of here?
你們兩個怎麼的？ 加起來要幹這個活110年？
A hundred and twenty.
120年
I'm telling you, you screw up dadly enough, you may try to fuck out your pension.
我可告訴你，如果砸透了 你們的養老金可沒戲了
You want to risk that?
真想冒這個險？
- Yeah. - Fuck yeah.
- 是的 - 絕對他媽的是！
406, Lieutenant
406，長官
406.
406.
OK, 406, what does that mean?
OK，406，到底什麼意思？
Ted Williams.
特德·威廉斯
Ted Williams' last hit at season back to 400...
特德·威廉斯的最後一個賽季 平均已達400分…
Sox's manager wants him to pension to protect his average, right?
紅襪的經理想讓他提早退休 保持紀錄，對吧？
The man's playing both games anyway, go six more ends up as 406 last guy ever hit over 400.
他到底還是比完最後兩場，還多拿了6分 打了406，成為最後一個過400的人
OK, fine, it's all yours.
OK，好吧，那就交給你們了
Just don't go moan and wail when some...
不過到時候別哭著來找我訴苦…
...traffic cop pulls your series killer over for speed, and he grab your 15 minutes of fame.
說什麼公交警察抓了一個超速行駛的人 正好是連環殺手，毀了你們一世英明
And you realized..., the ass hole could stand right there in front of you.
到時你們才意識到 這傢伙原來就在你們跟前
And it will take you a thousand light years to nail him.
而想要抓他卻得花掉 上千光年
Not offensive, Lieutenant. Light years measures distant, not time.
別介意，長官 光年是測距的，不是時間
Well thank you, Detective I will make a note of that.
謝謝，探長 我會記下來的
Ellis Lynde ,2003
埃利斯·林德，2003
This guy had a hisory of strolling gay bars. Pick out a 20, beat shit out of them.
這傢伙喜歡去同性戀酒吧 找年青人下手，然後將他們幹掉
Then he was found shot dead in his apartment.
後來被發現中槍 死在他的家中
The one was just doing this to get real close to the guy.
不知用什麼方法 兇手跟他距離很近
Blow his brains out, without any trouble.
把他的腦袋炸開了花 沒費一點勁
Leaves no finger prints. And obviously...
沒有任何指紋 而且很明顯…
take his private room.
還進過他的臥室
Okay, it could be murder number two, back from 04(2004).
OK，我們可以追溯 到2004年的案件…
I was shaking at the first coupla times that I killed in cold blood.
前幾次我冷血一樣殺人 手還有些抖
Keep thinking if I got caught, they keep you away of the force...
一直在想，如果我被捕了 那就沒了武力…
I wasn't worrying about the prison, but losing the gun and the shell, that's can't be.
我倒是不害怕進監獄 但交出槍和子彈，那可不行
I went to work the next day expect them feel different.
第二天我回去上班 想著他們會對我有所察覺
I thought everybody will look at me the way cops look at civilians knowing which one is dirty.
原以為每個人都會看著我 就像警察看著幾個人知道就誰有罪一樣
And they didn't.
可是他們沒有
That's when I knew I can keep on doing this.
那時我就明白 我可以繼續這麼幹下去
...foever.
…直到永遠
So..., next stop, Spider.
接下來，下一目標，蜘蛛
If we shut down his business, maybe he'll be a rap.
如果直接封了他的生意 他可能會發狂
We got a lawyer.
我們找了個律師
We need her to testify that she bought coke from him.
我們要她出庭作證 她在他那買了毒品
She was a good lawyer.
她是個好律師
Me and my partner paid a visit to Club 404 Harlem
我和我的搭檔去了一趟 404黑人夜總會
I worried about him.
我很擔心他
Tom Cowan has been my partner for almost 30 years.
湯姆·卡文已經跟我搭檔快30年了
He's the best cop I've ever seen.
他是我見過的最好的警察
I'm always the one follows him into the door.
我總是追隨他的思想
There was a bullet that was meant for me that slugged his torso.
本來有顆子彈是衝我來的 但他用身體擋住了
He was my role model.
他是我的楷模
The day I stopped trying to be Tom Cowan. Was the greatest day of my life.
我決定不再成為湯姆·卡文的那一天 是我一生中最幸福的一天
EVIDENCE Randall.
證據 蘭德爾
Hey.
嘿
Rooster.
風凰.
I was looking through the files on poetry boy.
我剛剛看了下 詩歌男的卷宗
That's an interesting way to pass your time.
你倒是挺會打發時間的
There was a gun found on Charles Randall when he was arrested.
查爾斯·蘭德爾被捕的時候 在他家中搜到了一把槍
Yeah?
對啊？
I know in other shootings, a gun was found at the scene
我知道其他的槍擊現場 也都有支槍
But there is a lot of similarities.
而且有很多共同點
So I mentioned it to Perez and Riley. I think someone should go to interview the prisoner.
於是我跟佩雷斯和羅林提了一嘴 我想最好有人去盤問一下蘭德爾
I think there may be a connection.
我覺得這裡邊可能有聯繫
That's an good idea. But not to Perez and Riley.
想法不錯 不過對佩雷斯和羅林就不是了
I mean you know those guys can make it just screwed it up.
你知道他們兩個的 很可能會把事搞砸了
This is too important.
這事太重要了
Turk and I will handle that Randall, okay?. Good work.
頑童和我會處理蘭德爾的，OK？ 幹的好
Detectives, Charles Randall.
探長，查爾斯·蘭德爾帶到
What fuck you two son of bitch want?
你們他媽兩個狗娘養的來幹嘛？
What a greeting.
就這麼問候客人？
Do you like poetry, Charles?
你愛做詩嗎，查爾斯？
What?
什麼？
Do you like poetry?
你愛不愛做詩？
Yeah.
愛！
Roses are red, violets are blue.
玫瑰真紅，紫羅蘭真藍
I wanna poke out your fucking eyes with my dick, you fuck.
我要用雞雞挖出你的雙眼 你他媽的
- How's that? - I thought it would rhyme, but it didn't.
- 這詩怎麼樣？ - 我以為會押韻，可惜沒有
Fuck you, fuck both of you. Get me out of here.
去你媽的，去你倆媽的 帶我回去
Why the fuck we wanna going up there?
我們兩個幹嘛 他媽的要跑去那？
What we look like if we didn't go?
如果不去 別人會怎麼看？
Did you relax?
放鬆了沒？
Relax.
放鬆了
Yeah, I just take it out on Karen later.
遲些我找凱倫發洩就行了
I more I'm willing it, the more impugn shot us.
我越有狠勁 她越喜歡
Sounds like fun.
聽起來不錯
Hey, you wanna take over my hands?
嘿，你想接我的班嗎？
Be careful, partner. Because I'm really special affected on women.
小心點，搭檔 我對女人很敏感
Go violent.
暴力點吧
Never.
絕不
You know, I can't look at the face of that piece of shit, like an idiot.
跟你說，我真不想多看一眼 那個垃圾的臉，像個白癡
Fuck him, he's where he belongs.
去他的，他罪有應得
Sorry about him, I'm really sorry.
對不起，關於這事 真不對起了
Stop pulling about it.
別再提了
Whatever happens, I'm not gonna take down with me.
不管發生什麼 我都不會牽扯到你
Don't worry about me, I'm all right. Believe me.
別擔心，我沒事 相信我
I don't know what I'm thinking, I just don't know how to think it.
真不知道我當時在想什麼 就是搞不明白
You know what were you thinking?
你知道你在想什麼嗎？
You were thinking about a ten year old girl... had her skull crashed.
你在想一個十歲的小女孩 被人無情的剝奪了生命
Yeah, I tried to stop you... But you know what? I admired you that day.
沒錯，我是想阻止你… 可你知道嗎？那天我很崇拜你
What you did...
你所做的事…
...that was righteous.
是正義的
And you don't second guess yourself or something like that.
你也用不著懷疑你自己 或者怎麼樣
Okay, I'm the killer.
OK，我是兇手
I'm the killer, I showed up. I shot the door.
我是兇手，我現身了 敲了門
Or your car window. Having some reasons, you opened your door.
或者車窗 出於某種原因，你打開了門
You rolled down the car window... for me.
或者搖開了車窗… 為我開的
So? Who am I?
那麼？我是誰呢？
Someone I know.
我認識的人
Maybe nice of the tits.
也許是美女
The poems, what about the poems.
詩呢，那些詩呢
You have to compose the poem before you got there, right?
你必須得在到那之前 把詩寫好，對吧？
Otherwise, well, you gonna blow the guy's brains, and sit down and write down the sonata?
不然，你轟了死者的腦袋 還要坐下來做首詩？
There's no prints on the poems.
詩上沒有指紋
So, probably I wore gloves when I wrote.
所以，很可能我是帶著手套寫的
You obviously know your victims, be turned to an easy access,
很明顯你認得死者 所以才能輕鬆進入房內
I guess they know you too, they must.
我猜他們也認得你 肯定認得
These guys are all scoundrels. They're not gonna trust anyone.
這些都是惡貫滿盈的人 他們誰也不會相信
They're not gonna open the door for anyone, especially they don't know.
不可能給任何人開門 更不用說不認識的
Yeah, yeah, but I'm more than know them.
對，對 但我不止認識他們
I know everything about them, I know their moves, their patterns, I know their schedules.
我還知道他們的每個細節 我知道他們的行為，習慣，甚至日程
Okay, so you follow them, stick them out.
OK，就是說你跟蹤他們 挖他們出來的
Anyone gonna say it?
有誰願意說出口嗎？
What?
什麼？
Fuck me.
媽的
- Right, it's a cop. - It's not.
- 對啊，是條子 - 不是
Let's slow down before we get away ahead our sight...
等等，慢點 別偏題太遠
- Come on! It's a cop. You know it. - Na, not cop. I don't know shit.
- 拜託！是條子，大家心知肚明 - 不，不是條子，我心不知肚不明
I'm telling you now, it's a cop. It's a cop, it's a cop.
那我告訴你，是條子 是條子，是條子
It ain't no cop, it's a cop, it's a cop. Why you keep always saying it's a cop, it's a cop...
不是條子，什麼是條子，是條子 你幹嘛一直不停的說是條子，是條子…
- Easy..., he's just saying that... - What are you talking about?
- 冷靜，他只是這麼說… - 你說什麼呢？
I know what he's saying!
我知道他說的什麼意思！
And I'm saying it's bullshit!
而我說那是胡扯！
It should be, with the fuck... but don't say it's a cop.
就算是，去他媽的 但別說他是條子
So, what about dinner?
晚飯怎麼辦？
I'm feeling like going out.
我看還是出去吃吧
Where?
去哪？
I don't care, you're the one going.
我不管，是你出去又不是我
What is your problem?
你怎麼回事？
No problme.
沒怎麼
If you like hanging around, be my guest.
如果你想出去逛下 悉聽尊便
I don't feel like going out.
我不想出去
Fine.
好吧
Just don't bug me, it's the part of my day and I don't need your fucking help.
別煩我就行，現在是一天中我最爽的時候 不需要你的雞雞幫忙
So, you only fuck cops?
你只跟條子上床？
Once in a while, do a fireman and an ex-con.
時不時的 會跟消防隊員或蹲過牢的人
Not one person you got, ha?
口味還挺廣的啊
I love some respectful fireman.
我更喜歡有氣魄的消防員
Fuck you.
去你媽的
You know why they take away your espantoon when hanging up your uniform?
你知道為什麼你停職的時候 他們就收你的警具嗎？
No.
不知道
They don't trust you with it.
他們不相信你
And now I wouldn't trus myself either, sure you probably love that.
現在我自己也不相信我自己了 這下你肯定高興了
Too bad you never met Van Luytens, you two really were ahead of great.
可惜你跟范·魯特斯沒上過床 你們兩個可不只是絕配那麼簡單
That somebody finnal brought Jonathan(Luytens) down, the dick little fuck.
把那個垃圾強姦犯 幹掉的那個牛人
And that, that's what I like to meet.
才是我想要會一會的
Maybe you're gonna get your wish one day.
也許有天你的美夢會成真
They think it's a cop.
他們認為他是個警察
- Make sense. - Bullshit. That' just some fucking,  psychopath.
- 有道理 - 胡扯，他就是個變態神精病
Oh.. There is plenty of those on the job.
警局裡這樣的人可不少哦
You sleeping well?
你睡眠好嗎？
- Not really. - Yeah.
- 不太好 - 很好
Eating well?
飲食好嗎？
- No. - Yeah.
- 不好 - 好
- Any recuring nightmares? - Yeah, then I'm stuck in a room with you forever.
- 有沒有重複性的噩夢？ - 有啊，後來我就一直跟你卡在一個屋子裡了
Nope.
沒有
You think it fit if return to the duty?
你覺得可以回去復職了嗎？
- Abso-fucking-lutely. - Yeah.
- 絕他媽的對！ - 是的
- Have you thinked about retirement? - You mean...
- 有沒有想過退休？ - 你是說…
death with benefits?
揣著養老金等死？
Or something like?
或者其他什麼的？
Did you think about retirement?
你有沒有想過退休？
Not really.
沒想過
What do I look forward? Sailing my 26 shipset in the bay?
退了之後幹嘛？ 去海邊滑我26英尺的小船？
Umpire of cop softball?
當一名警局壘球裁判？
How about a cop security work?
警察保安工作怎麼樣？
- Too dangerous. - So what are you gonna do?
- 太危險了 - 那你打算幹什麼？
Maybe I buy a boat.
或許我買條小船
All right, look, I don't if I believe this, but I'm gonna just throw this out that you guys say...
聽著，不管你們信不信 我只是隨便說說，你們不是說…
We are looking for one of our own.
我們其實在查內部的人嗎？
But what if it was an ex-cop?
但如果是一名「前警察」怎麼辦？
Somebody wears an ex-uniform.
一個曾經穿過制服的人
You got one in your mind?
你有目標嗎？
He's thinking about Martin Baum.
他說的是馬丁·鮑姆
An old Lieutenant.
一個老警局長官
So what' the doing with him?
他怎麼了？
He got fired a few years ago.
幾年前被撤職了
I'm not saying there is a motive, but he knows all the victims.
我並不是說一定有什麼動機 但他認識這些死者
Yeah, but Turk, I knew most of these guys.
對，可是頑童，我也認識大多數死者
So and you, Riley, Perez, even Corelli.
還有你，羅林，佩雷斯，甚至克萊利
I just thew it out there.
我只是把這事說出來而已
Maybe you killed them.
也許就是你殺的
Yeah, I did.
沒錯，就是我
Poems, and the place of the weapon, is the all we got linked to the kills.
那些詩，再場的槍支 我們只有這些線索
Which means what we gotta do now is getting hope on the forensics.
就是說我們只能 寄希望於物證分析署了
Let's deal with your poem, We already got your girl working on that.
我們來處理你說的詩 我們已經讓你的女友著手了
That's right, Cowcen, we've been a long week, that was big.
沒錯，已經幹了一周了 真是爽啊
What did you say?
你剛才說什麼？
Ha, here we go again.
又來了
Watch you mouth.
說話小心點
Leave anything about it, Karen and Simon are just history, don't woryy about it.
別理他，凱倫和西蒙只是工作上的往來 別擔心這個
Well, he's just speaking for himself?
那他剛才是跟他自己說話呢啊？
Yeah, I just speak for myself. Let me speak for myself please. Fuck you! Turk!
是，我就是跟我自己說的 讓我跟我自己說個夠：「去你媽的!頑童！」
Well I'm gonna let you have this fucking ball...
我要讓你嘗嘗我這拳頭…
- You better more than that. - You, put your balls in your pocket.
- 你最好來點厲害的 - 你，收起你的拳頭
And you, fellow officers.
還有你們，高級督察
You, curtsey for the fellow professional.
你，給督察專家賠個禮
Please!
拜託！
We're gonna move on here now?
這回可以繼續了嗎？
Here we are going, where were we?
繼續，說到哪了？
- Talking about Martin Baum. - What's the story.
- 在說馬丁·鮑姆 - 他是什麼情況？
Some guys I knew got caught taking money. Baum stood off to them, tried to cover it up.
他認識幾個人，因偷錢而被捕 鮑姆裝做不認識，想以此脫身
He do time?
他坐牢了？
Well they put charges on him, then he plead and resigned.
他們起訴他了 於是他申請辭職了
So what's the big for deal?
這有什麼關係？
I could have lied to protect him, but I didin't.
我本來可以做偽證幫他 但我沒有
Okay, but there's gotta be for deal. Why not go after you? Why not kill you?
OK，但還是沒關係 為什麼他不找你？為什麼不殺你？
Why going out there like a serial killer? It doesn't make sense.
為什麼跑出去做個連環殺手？ 不合邏輯啊
- How do I know, I'm just telling you. - Well, I'm telling you, it doesn't make any sense.
- 我怎麼知道，我只是講事實 - 但我是講邏輯，這不合邏輯
I'm throwing that out, I'm saying.
我只是把這事說出來 我說過了
- You wanna check that out, I won't give a shit. - It doesn't make any sense.
- 如果你想查，我屁也不放一個 - 這完全不符合邏輯
You are the one think he's a cop. I'm just saying he's cop with a chip on his shoulder.
是你覺得兇手是個條子 我只是說鮑姆是個有憤世情緒的條子
Check it out if you want...
如果你想查，請自便…
Just calm down, give us a better reason that Baum could be a suspect, okay?
冷靜點，我們只是想聽一個 更合理的理由，OK？
PMS, gotta be.
月經不快，肯定是
Hey, guys.
嘿，兩位
What's going on?
你在幹嘛？
Oh, I came over here bringing you the FBI report in the paper and handwriting.
我給你送FBI的報告 一份打印的，一份手寫的
You don't have any problem with me looking around inside?
我在這裡看看 沒事吧？
Collect and process for your deal.
順便學習一下你們的經驗
No problem.
沒問題
- Put them back. - I mean, this is fascinating.
- 放回去 - 我是說，這真是好極了
Come on, come on. Let's go, let's go. Come on, let's go.
過來，過來 出去，咱們出去，快
Hey, get your hands off me.
嘿，把你的手拿開
Ah, I'll give you a little privacy. I don't want to obstruct you.
我得給你們點私人空間 我可不想掃了你們的興
You are afraid of me looking at these files? Ah? Is that it?
你害怕我看這些文件？ 是不是？
Okay, I'm gone. Enjoy it.
OK，我走了 慢慢享受
What is it with you? What is it with you?!
你怎麼回事？
I'm sorry about last night, okay?
昨晚對不起，OK？
I really am, it's a habit. Habits can be broken, all right?
真的，那只是個習慣 習慣可以改的，行嗎？
- Oh, that's bullshit. - No.
- 全是胡扯 - 不
I'm totally serious, all right?
我是絕對認真的，行嗎？
It's not bullshit.
不是胡扯
Really.
真的
Why you think Turk was so cool to take the lead on the poetry boy case?
你說頑童為什麼這麼急著 想帶頭查這個案子？
To keep us from finding the killer man. That's what I'll do if I'll cover my tracks.
就是不想讓咱們查出兇手 如果我按部就班，肯定能查出來
He takes us on this Baum state, 'cause he wants us to miss direction.
他卻非搞個鮑姆出來 就是想擾亂咱們的視聽
Make sense.
有道理
I hate that Turk man.
我討厭那個老頑童
Hey, it's coming here, coming here.
嘿，來了，來了
It's 2:45 in the moring.
凌晨2點45分
It's the killing time? I don't think it's the killing time.
是殺人時間？ 不像是殺人時間嘛
Come on, Baum, go to kill someone in there.
上啊，鮑姆，進去殺個痛快
Yeah, kill Turk, man, he's the one set you up. Do us all the favour.
對，殺了頑童，是他設計你的 也算是幫我們一個大忙
Did you see Turk's full mark scores record these years?
你看了頑童這幾年的射擊記錄沒
It's ridiculous. Service in 99, 70 yard in 100.
簡直不可思議 99年，70碼(64米)外全部中十環
Combat association award, department commedations.
搏擊聯合會大獎 處級以上榮譽證書
This guy can take your life in more than 50 yards.
這傢伙在50碼(45.7米)以外要你的小命 如探囊取物
Through the computer to check this man, a one straight look.
如果你用電腦查查這傢伙 掃一眼就知道
- What about Corelli, she came up with anything new? - No, not yet.
- 克萊利那邊怎麼樣？有新發現沒？ - 沒，還沒有
If Baum kills somebody, I don't wanna speak in the car and wait when it happens, okay?
如果鮑姆想殺人，我可不想在這裡干做著 等著人被殺，OK？
I'll go.
我去
Attaboy, Teddy, attaboy. I'm proud of you, son.
振做點，特裡，振做點 以為為榮，寶貝
You are Perez, right?
你就是佩雷斯，對吧？
Yeah.
是的
I'm Martin Baum.
我是馬丁·鮑姆
I got a permit for this.
我是有持槍證的
I worked as security for the Dimmer District.
我現在在做私人保鏢
So, you figure it's a cop doing the poetry killings?
這麼說你們查出 這個詩歌男是個警察？
So, "let's check out Baum", "I think he's gotten wrong deal".
於是就「咱們去查查鮑姆吧」 「我想他肯定有問題」
So that's sort of words he says?
他是不是這麼說的？
- Do you think he got the wrong deal? - Damn straight.
- 你覺得他搞錯了？ - 那還用說
- Life sucks. - Yeah.
- 生活不易啊 - 沒錯
- Everything is okay? Simon? - Teddy, what the fuck where you, man?
- 沒事吧，西蒙？ - 特裡，你他媽跑哪去了？
- How are you doing? - I think you want to tell us someting, Lieutenant Baum.
- 嗨，你好 - 我看你是有事要跟我們說，鮑姆長官
I got something for you in my pocket.
我兜裡有東西給你們
Passport, credit card receipts, boarding passes...
我的護照，信用卡票據 過境簽證…
The day he was killed, I was escorting a client to Brazili.
他被殺那天 我剛好送客戶去巴西
"If he is truelly penitent, sincere absolution,"
「如果他真心悔過 實意贖罪」
"It must be granted to him."
「上蒼必會接受他」
"Your name doesn't ring your bell."
「你的名字 並未換起我的記憶」
"But I had so many altar boys over the years."
「但這些年來 我有過太多的侍者」
So many altar boys that so hard to remember their names.
侍者太多 以致於無法記住他們的名字
My name is Detective David Fisk, Detective first grade.
我的名字是大衛·費斯克 一級探長
You may not remeber me now, but I guarantee you'll remeber my name for you rest of you life.
現在你可能不記得我了，但我保證 你的後半輩子永遠忘不了我
Farther Connel, may him rot in hell.
康奈爾神父，願他永入地獄
Thirteen down, one to go.
第十三個，還剩一個
White underwear, blue overknee.
白底褲，藍短褲
Same style, where's the treaters?
同樣的手法 筆錄官在哪？
I am removing a card that has been inserted into the rump of the deceased.
我正從死者臀部取出 一張卡片
And placing it into an plastic evidence bag.
然後將其裝入一個證據密封袋中
- I'll be right back. - All right.
- 我馬上回來 - 好的
Hey. It's another one, handwritten.
嘿，這又來一個 手寫詩
THE OLD MAN WHO THE CHILDREN TRUST. UNABLE TO CONTROL HIS LUST.
「孩子奉他為神」 「他卻守不住慾望的門」
ASHES TO ASHES, DUST TO DUST.
「灰是灰，塵是塵」
THE CHURCH CAN'T SOPT HIM SOMEONE MUST.
「上天他不管 自有管他的人」
I'll see what else I can find.
我去看看還有什麼發現
What's my ringing?
想起什麼了？
Farther Connel gave my first communion... back in Benslus.
我的第一個聖餐禮 是康奈爾神父給我做的，在本斯勒
- Hey, guys, sorry we didn't got a chance to call. - Okay, I bet you are.
- 嘿，夥計，不好意思沒來得及打電話 - OK，我猜也是
Go over there, check and look around, we compare notes later. Okay?
去裡面看看，查一查記一記 遲些我們對筆記，OK？
Look like our friend settled an old score to Priest.
看來我們的老朋友 跟牧師有舊仇
- Left him pants down. - Oh, come on.
- 把他被子都扒了 - 噢，不是吧
- Oh, look. - Come on, don't talk like that.
- 噢，去看吶 - 拜託，別那個樣子說話嘛
Hey, look at it yourself.
嘿，自己過去看嘛
Listen, he's gonna tell us that Lieutenat Baum was the altar boy here.
聽吧，他肯定又要跟咱們說 鮑姆長官是這裡的侍者
Don't even buy it, this two guys just fucking stink.
別理它 這兩個傢伙只會攪事
Look, Doctor, you got the poems, it is possible, right?... that this guy is a cop.
聽著，醫生，你看到詩了 這是可能的，對吧？…這人是個警察
Na, I've never seen it. I've never even heard about a cop serial killer.
不，我沒看出來 沒聽過什麼警察連環殺手
Come on, girls. Let's go, let's go.
加油，姑娘們 衝啊，衝啊
Go, go, go...
快，快，快…
Doc., give us a tip. How can we catch this guy?
醫生，給點建議 怎麼才能抓到這小子？
Not to worry about that. He wants to get caught.
這個不用擔心 他就是想被抓到
You want any better place for lunch?
不想找個好點的地方吃中飯？
- I want to thank you. - About spider?
- 我想說謝謝你 - 你指蜘蛛的事？
Yeah, and for looking after me at the hospital. And your encouragement.
是的，還有在醫院照顧我 鼓勵我
- Why would he want that? - After while getting away with it isn't enough.
- 他怎麼會這麼想？ - 輕而易舉就逃脫，不能讓他得到滿足
So, is your daughter in the team?
你女兒在隊裡？
No, she used to play, bu not she's 25 living in California.
沒，她以前打過 現在已經25歲了，住在加州
- Working as a nurse. - And her mother?
- 是名護士 - 她媽媽呢？
Her mother died when she was very young.
她很小的時候 她媽媽就去世了
He wants everybody to know that he got away with it.
他想讓所有人都知道 他想逃就能逃
Show everybody just how brilliant he is.
讓所有人知道 他是多麼聰明
Most of these killings acquitted right front of Rooster and his face, right?
大部份死者都曾在 風凰和他面前被判無罪，對吧？
And he also threatened to kill the lams in front of a hundred of witness,
而且當著那麼多人的面 他曾揚言要殺死那些人
then he make this crazy bullshit sounds going after Lieutenant Baum.
然後他又把這些事 全都推到鮑姆長官身上
- Right? Did he? - Yes, he did.
- 是吧，沒錯吧？ - 是，沒錯
- Why?Why?... - You, you, ...
- 為什麼？為什麼？… - 你，你…
You gotta show me more than than that, so far you got shit.
你得拿點實際的 說了半天全是胡扯
- Give him more, man. - You want more? How about the church records?
- 給他點實際的 - 想看點實際的？不如看看這個教堂的記錄
There was that Turk so diligently pursuing.
頑童在這上面可花了不少功夫
Now turns out, our most recently victim, the Farther Connel, has moved...
現在看來，這名死者 這個康奈爾神父，曾經遷移過…
... all over the places, eight parish in twenty years. Why would he do that as a Catholic priest?
所有這些地方，20年間，8個教區 一個天主教神父幹嘛費這周折？
It's obviously. He's giving the children more than communion behind the altar.
很明顯，他給小孩們做的 可不僅僅是聖餐禮那麼簡單
Turk already even knows it when this guy was a child. It's very plausible.
而頑童小時候就已經知道了 還用我多說嗎？
So, this priest, Farther Connel, gave you the first Holy Communion?
這個牧師，康奈爾神父 給你做的首個聖餐禮？
- He did. - Did he ever try to do anything in improper?
- 對，是他 - 他有沒有做些出格的事？
- I mean... - I know what you mean, no, never.
- 我指的是… - 我明白你的意思，沒，從沒有過
Okay, fine. Is there any reason why somebody out there might think that he did.
OK，好吧，那有什麼特別的原因 會使得有人覺得他做過？
No, am I a suspect? Lieutenant?
沒，我成嫌疑犯了？ 長官？
No, but these buddies are starting to smell...,
沒有，但風聲已經傳開了…
a lof of it is drifting in your direction.
其中很多漂向了你
- Drifting or being pushed? - What can I say?
- 漂的，還是吹的？ - 我能說什麼呢？
You got connections with most of the victims. You are not exactly Mother Teresa.
你跟很多死者都有干係 你又不是聖母特蕾莎
- I never had any problem with that priest. - Okay, okay, fine.
- 我跟那牧師之間沒任何問題 - OK，OK，好吧
Let's settle this.
就當我沒說過
- I had a talk with Riley and Perez. - Good cops.
- 我跟羅林和佩雷斯聊過了 - 好警察
-Don't fuck around, okay? Just listen. - I'm listening.
- 別扯沒用的，OK？好好聽著 - 我聽著呢
They think Turk maybe our guy.
他們覺得頑童可能就是那個人
Oh, man, I gotta tell you from where I'm sitting that is so fucking funny.
我可以對著凳子發誓 這說法可笑致極
You can't take that seriously? Right?
你不會當真的吧？對吧？
Everybody has pretty much accepted that that fact we are chasing one of our own.
大家都認同 兇手是我們中的一員
But it ain't Turk. Sure as I'm sitting here ain't the guy.
但不會是頑童 禿子頭上的虱子，還用我說麼
- You know that? - Yes, I do.
- 你又知道？ - 對，我知道
- How do you know that? - Because I know it.
- 你怎麼知道的？ - 因為我知道
I know it to a moral certainty. Okay?
我百分之百的知道，OK？
This priest, this father Connel, he was Turk's priest when he was a kid.
這個牧師，康奈爾神父 頑童小的時候，他就是頑童的牧師了
- He told you that. - But he didn't tell me this priest was a child molester.
- 他早就告訴你了 - 但他沒告訴我這個牧師有戀童癖
- I can't believe it. - Believe it.
- 我不信！ - 你還是信吧
Turk is a good guy. He is one of the best cops.
頑童是個好人 他是最好的警察之一
Don't tell me what I gotta do!
不用你告訴我該怎麼辦！
Don't say a god damn word to him about this either, or you're finished.
這事一個字也不要跟他提 不然連你一塊玩完
- Can I speak now? - Do pray.
- 我可以說話了嗎？ - 請便
He cares. You know what I'm saying?
他在乎！ 懂我的意思嗎？
Turk cares about people.
頑童在乎別人
I know he once around like pitbull on crack sometimes, it doesn't matter.
我知道他有時像條瘋狗 但這無關緊要
He cares about protecting people.
他在乎如何保護別人
And if you don't back him, you will regret it.
而如果你不罩著他 你肯定會後悔
- Oh, Jesus! - I'm sorry.
- 噢，上帝！ - 不好意思
I never rattled anyone caged before. You got a minute?
我從沒跟關在籠子裡的人聊過天 有空嗎？
Yeah, what's up?
有，什麼事？
You know me and Turk are buddies, right?
你知道我跟頑童是好兄弟，對吧？
- Of course. - I'll do anything for him.
- 當然了 - 我會為他做任何事
He will do anything for you.
他也會為你做任何事
- Would you? - Would I what?
- 你會嗎？ - 什麼我會嗎？
Would you do anything for him?
你會他為做任何事嗎？
I don't know,..., I..., where is this going?
我沒明白，到底怎麼回事？
- He wants to have sex on me. - Really?
- 他想跟我上床 - 真的？
You wouldn't mind. But that's not why I'm here.
你不會介意吧？ 不過我不是為這個來的
Okay, why are you here?
OK，那是為了什麼？
Where were you the night Rambo was killed?
蘭博被殺當晚 你在哪？
And Trager, any alibi for those nights?
還有特雷格 那幾晚你有不在場的證據嗎？
I mean did you even know these guys before they were murdered?
我是想說，甚至他們被殺之前 你認識他們嗎？
- Well, now I learned. - You can't be comfortable when I talk like that.
- 現在我明白了 - 我這麼說話你肯定不舒服
And you look like you are guilty while you are not guilty.
而且就算你沒罪 你卻看想來挺有罪
I know that, you didn't kill those guys, didn't you?
我知道，你沒殺他們 是不是？
Now you know what Turk feels.
現在你知道頑童的感受了吧
I need you to get me some information...discreetly.
我想讓你幫我弄些資料… 偷偷的
Would you do that for me?
你願意幫我嗎？
- You got it, absolutely. - Solve these fucking murders.
- 好，沒問題 - 趁早解決些殺人犯
- Hey, boy genius. - Pefect time, buddy.
- 嘿，天才神探 - 真是時候，老兄
Listen, you really worked on Hingis, didn't you? He was on work boubt my partner.
聽著，你跟辛吉斯聊過了，是吧？ 他現在開始懷疑我的搭檔了
Good, he should be.
很好，他就該這樣
I think we should just sit down and see what we can do to square things, okay?
我想咱們最好坐下來好好聊聊 有些事需要圓潤一下，OK？
- All right, then we meet at Trails at eight pm. - Can you make that nine?
- 好吧，晚上八點，老地方見 - 九點可以嗎？
- I gotta meet an old friend. - Yeah sure, whatever you want.
- 我要去見個老朋友 - 沒問題，隨你
Hey, fellows.
嘿，夥計們
Thanks for coming.
謝謝賞光
- This is Cheryl Brooks. - Helllo Cheryl Brooks.
- 這位是謝麗爾·布魯克斯 - 你好，謝麗爾·布魯克斯
Cheryl got something to tell you.
謝麗爾有事要跟你們說
My daughter, Lynn, died four years ago.
我女兒，林恩，四年前死了
She was ten years old, she was raped, and she was murdered.
當時她10歲，先被人強姦 然後被殺害
The guy was, living with me, name Charles.
兇手是，跟我一起生活的男人 叫查爾斯·蘭德爾
- Charles Randall. - Yeah, Charles Randall, he did it.
- 查爾斯·蘭德爾 - 對，查爾斯·蘭德爾，是他幹的
- So why are you telling us this? - Because he got off for that.
- 跟我們說這個幹嘛？ - 因為最後他無罪釋放了
He was acquitted in trial.
庭審時被判無罪
- Because...? - Because...
- 因為…？ - 因為…
- I testified for him. - You did what?
- 我出庭為他作證 - 你什麼？
I said he was with me.
我說他當時跟我在一起 （即：有不在場的證據）
You see, Cheryl here is a very forgiving person... unlike her hard asses.
看，謝麗爾是個仁慈的人… 不像她的混蛋男人
- He threatened to kill me. - Okay, Cheryl, okay.
- 他威脅要殺死我 - 好了，謝麗爾，OK
You say "goodbye" to the nice officers.
跟好心警官們說「拜拜」吧
Here go on, back home, and don't drink youself to dead.
拿著這個，回家吧 別喝太多酒
Okay, ..., so...
OK
I wanna hear you to say it. Come on, say it.
我想聽你親口說出來 說啊
We planted the gun in Randall's apartment. Okay?
是我們藏了槍在蘭德爾家，嫁禍給他的 OK？
- I said it. Happy? - Thank you.
- 我已經說了，高興了吧 - 謝了
- Yes, I am. - I'll do it again if I had to.
- 是，高興 - 如果有必要，我還會幹
Because that fucking maggot could run away for all eternity. I sleep just fine.
因為如果人人都袖手旁觀 這個混蛋可能永遠消遙法外
So what you want from us?
那你想要我們怎麼樣？
Well, you guys think my partner is this serial killer.
你們兩個認為 我的搭檔是連環殺手
You are way off. You like Turk for this thing? Go have your fun.
錯的離譜 你們想設計套他？悉聽尊便
I'll go along with you. I even help you.
我跟你們合作 甚至還可以幫你們
But do not drag off Charles Randall at that fucking gun.
但千萬別管 查爾斯·蘭德爾和槍的事
Because if he walked out of jail, he's gonna end of dead.
因為如果他一旦出了大牢的門 腦袋就會開花
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
I'll put tools to his fucking head...,
我會打爛他的頭…
...myself.
…我親自
Done deal.
信不信由你
My grandmother loved opera..., she supported us by sewing.
我的奶奶很喜歡歌劇 她靠幫人縫補衣服養活我們
I used to thread needles..., for my grand mother.
我還幫她給針穿過線…
Devote all the money to church.
她把所有的錢 都捐給教堂了
- You admired her? - I worshiped her.
- 你欽佩她？ - 我視她為神
Rooster? Has religious, goes to church.
風凰？信教，經常去教堂
How about you?
你呢？
"Our job is to keep 99% of the population safe from the other 1%."
「我們的工作就是 讓99%的人群遠離另外那1%」
"The problem is we have spent half of our life with that 1%,"
「可問題是，我們用大半輩子 跟那另外的1%周旋」
"and the better we do that job, the less the other 99% think they need us."
「事情處理的越好 那99%越覺得我們的存在沒有必要」
They clueless.
「一群無能的人」
"The only ones are paying attention on the street are the cops and the criminals."
「街上有精神的人 除了警察就是罪犯」
"Everyone else just going somewhere..., or shopping."
「其他的要麼去哪出遊… 要麼去逛商場」
I got an order here, placing you on a more strict duty.
我收到指令 調你到限區工作
That means you work at your desk. You may want to cooperate with the shrink.
就是說你只能做文案工作了 也許你想跟心理醫生好好合作一下
Next time you want to meet, And you two will meet again.
下次你們想見面 會更容易了
Who my fucking heals..., who my fucking heals?!
去他媽的心理治療… 去他媽的心理治療！
I'm gonna fucking hole that mother fuck Perez a bullet right through his fucking head for puting through this bullshit.
我他媽要在佩雷斯頭上 用子彈開個洞！
Fuck! I'm gonna kill that mother fucker.
媽的！我他媽的要宰了他！
Calm down, what hell is it? You are making all the wrong move.
冷靜一下，你怎麼搞的？ 這麼沉不氣呢
What are you talking about? This ain't just a chess game, partner!
你說什麼風涼話！ 這可不是什麼象棋比賽，老兄！
Who knows, maybe it is.
誰知道呢，也許就是
You go after Perez now, you know who's gonna happy? You're gonna walk right into his trap.
你現在去找佩雷斯，你猜誰最高興？ 你正好掉到他設的套裡
You ARE! He's just waiting for you.
毫無疑問！ 他正等著你呢
Fuck Hingis, fuck Hingls believe him.
媽的辛吉斯，他媽的辛吉斯竟然相信他
actually fucking believe that mother fucker Perez.
竟然相信他媽的 混蛋佩雷斯
Stay back, wait. Wait for the right time...,
沉住氣，別著急 等時機一到…
...then fire away. Not now, now is not the right time.
就一發沖天 現在不行，現在時機還未到
Believe me.
相信我
You believe me? Now is not the time.
相信我不？ 現在還不是時候
Hey, Turk, I gotta skip tonight. My class run late.
嘿，頑童，今晚的約會得取消了 我的課落得太多了
But I will see you tomorrow, right?
但明天我會找你的，好嗎？
And I'm sorry about what happened between you and Lieutenant Hingis yesterday.
還有，昨天你跟辛吉斯長官的事 我很抱歉
It's gonna be fine, it will blow over. People will just..., I know it's cary, people over reacting.
會好起來的，一切都會過去的 有時候，有時候人就是反應過激
All right? Good night.
好嗎？晚安
"It's a cop, it's a cop, it's a cop..."
「是個條子，是個條子，是個條子…」
What you got for me, goodlooking?
給我帶了什麼好東西 美女？
Mark my words, there is a reason Perez coming for me.
等著瞧吧 佩雷斯盯上我肯定是有原因的
Perez is too smart to be that stupid.
佩雷斯還不至於那麼蠢
For one thing that college boy crapped? That's bullshit.
他還說自已是什麼大學畢業 全是扯淡
- He did one year, that's all, only one year. - Okay.
- 才上了一年，就那麼一年 - OK
They threw him up, threw out the influence.
是大家吹的 大夥兒把他捧高的
And I hear from the 2-40 Mister Dabet and Captain Larry the guy is totally fucking ass hole.
我從2-40小組那聽說 這小子整個一混球
BMW 3rd series, Mercedes CLK, cracked (Talking about Car Wars Game)
寶馬三系列，梅賽德斯CLK 被毀了（Car Wars遊戲）
BMW 7th series, the biggest engine, that's what I shut out begin.
寶馬七系列，最大號的引擎 一開始就被我滅了
If they shoot at you, you sure wanna get the fuck out there...
如果他們開槍射你 你就會後悔進了進去…
Bentley is very good, because...
賓利很棒，因為…
... in fucked two prostitutes in the back seat.
在後座可以同時 干兩個雞
And mount flame thrower on hood. Da. (Yeah?)
引擎罩上還可以裝噴火器 是不？
Da.(Yeah.)
是
Fuck..., fuck in the corner. Are you kidding me?
媽的…，媽的就在拐角處 你涮我呢啊？
You know anyone of those neandertals?
你認識那些土包子嗎？
Yeah, the whuped is Johcey Ancey from Pansina, a Gambino guy.
嗯，贏的那個是喬西·恩斯 黑手黨的人
And, what about Ivan?
那，那個俄國佬呢？
Russian guy, Yevgeny Mugalat, enforce for Guyense, works for Gambino slogger.
俄國人，葉夫根尼·馬格來特 也是黑手黨，打手並負責催債
- She's against to me. - I know she's against to you.
- 她最近總是針對我 - 我知道她在針對你
She's against to me too, you know. I take it in and let it out..., on my own terms.
她也針對我 我是聽之任之，處之泰然
I bet you didn't write one word down on that little notebook, Prosky gave us.
我敢說你肯定沒用那個筆記本 普羅斯基給我們的那個
Of course not, did you?
當然沒用，你用了？
Yeah, it's great.
是啊，很管用
It helps me, puts things in perspective.
幫了我不少 把很多事情理順了
You know what I'm saying? Write it down, get it out.
懂我的意思嗎？ 流於筆尖，止於心頭
- You should try this. - Let me have a look.
- 你真該試試 - 讓我看看
This belongs to me, private.
這是我的，私人的
- You won't let see it? - It's my heart. No, sir.
- 不想讓我看？ - 是我的心肝，不行，先生
I just got sick of the whole fucking game. Run around, looking for clues, making arrest.
這警察抓小偷的遊戲著實讓我噁心 到處奔波，搜集證物，緝拿歸案
Write report, testify, got deals, with all those so much fucking bullshit.
案情報告，證人證詞，黑白交易 全是他媽的狗屁胡扯
Detective...
警官…
Then it will get reall simple.
這樣事情就簡單多了
Yeah, Detective Perez is here. Hey, Riley, what's up?
是，我是佩雷斯探長 嘿，羅林，怎麼了？
I hate scumbags, I like shooting people, why was I giving up?
我討厭流氓，喜歡用槍打人 為什麼要放棄呢？
Hey, look, I set for a meeting with Rooster tomorrow.
我約了風凰明天一起見面
Yeah, fast. I don't wanna Turk know anything.
對，要快 我不想讓頑童收到風
A retirement paryt? A gold watch? Handshake with mayor? My name on some fucking plaque?
退休晚宴？黃金手錶？市長慰問？ 他媽的掛到牆上的虛名？
What the fucking deal! It's better this way.
都他媽白扯！ 這才是最好的一條路
Now everybody knows who I was and where I stood.
現在每個人都知道我是誰了 知道我在哪了
Hey, it's me.
嘿，是我
Listen, I think somebody following me. Here, home.
聽著，我覺得有人在跟蹤我 這裡，在我家
He's outside right now. Can you..., ah...
他現在就在外面 你能不能…
...come over, just call me back, okay?
過來一趟 給我回電話，OK？
All right.
好了
Come on, open the door.
快點，把門打開
Turk.
頑童
- I just called you. - Put the gun down.
- 我剛給你打的電話 - 把槍放下
- There's car following me. - Put the gun down! Put the gun down.
- 有個車一直跟著我 - 把槍放下！把槍放下！
- Have you got something to tell me? - About what?
- 難道你沒話要跟我說？ - 什麼話？
- Trager, Randall... - Did you sneak into my apartment...
- 特雷格, 蘭德爾... - 你是不是潛進我的房間…
What are you doing in your computer?
你最近在用電腦幹什麼？
I was checking all the links in the case.
我只是查查 案子幾處的關聯
Are you hiding something from me?
你在藏什麼東西？
Just received this, it's a poem.
剛收到的，是首詩
A poem? That was mention, ha?
一首詩？這下有意思了
The handwriting, doesn't ever match. It's a fake.
這字跡，根本不對 是仿寫的
Well, did you write it? Did you wite it?
難道是你寫的？ 是不是你寫的？
What hell is this going on here?
這到底是怎麼回事？
You are spending a lot of time with Perez, aren't you?
你跟佩雷斯走的很近 是不是？
Yeah, but we are working on the case.
是，但我們是在查案子
- What..., are you jealous? - Can I trust you?
- 怎麼，你吃醋了？ - 我能信得過你嗎？
- Yes. - Okay.
- 能 - OK
Give me anything and everything that you can find out about Perez, Riley...
把你能弄到的所有的 有關佩雷斯，羅林的資料都給我
...and they know about me.
還有他們掌握的我的資料
Everything, Karen, don't play me.
所有，凱倫 別耍花樣
I am leaning much poor of you into saying "that is a cop".
我越來越覺得兇手不是個警察
Well, tell you what, I'm moving passed the leaning stage,
我跟你說 我已經不是「覺得」了
and moving towards the..., I know for sure, to fucking cop stage.
我已經十分肯定 他就是個警察
...considering how your police shot a shit out of my house.
看看你敬愛的警察 是怎麼打爛我的房子的
Oh, my god, ..., are you hurt?
噢，天哪… 你受傷沒？
Am I hurt..., am I hurt, he wants to know if am I hurt.
我受傷沒，我受傷沒 他想知道我受傷沒
Actually he's dead.
事實上他已經死了
His name was Mugalat.
他的名字叫馬格來特
- The guy we saw at SALERNOS in the night. - Yeah.
- 那晚我們在餐廳見到的那小子？ - 對
He's in the Intensive Case at St. Luke's.
在聖·盧卡斯的急救中心
They think he's the guy chopped off Yakov Prosty's head.
他們認為他就是把尤克·普羅斯蒂 腦袋割掉的那個兇手
So what do you think? You think he's a victim or could be a suspect?
你怎麼看？ 一個受害者？又或是一名嫌疑犯？
I don't know, but either way, I think it's gonna be fun.
不知道，不過不管哪一個 我看這事都挺有意思
Doctor, what's the story?
醫生，什麼情況？
The man is acest humanbeing that I ever come into contact with.
這傢伙真是我見過的 最牛的人
- We took six bullets out of him. - Six?!
- 我們從他體內取出六顆子彈 - 六顆？！
Three for the night he was wounded, three for previous shootings.
三顆是他被擊當晚的 三顆是以前的
The was an ank(tank).
這人整個一坦克
Do you mind if I talk to him a little bit?
我能跟他說兩句話嗎？
- His jaws are very short. But go ahead. - That's okay.
- 他的下巴傷了，但你可以試試 - 沒事
I'll ask questions, so he can just grunt.
我來問，他哼聲就行了
Hey, wake up. Wake up, you big fucking crazy man.
嘿，醒醒 醒醒，你這個大號猛男
He wants me to speak Russian?
他想讓我講俄語？
I think this Russian killing machine could be our first eyewitness.
我看這個俄國殺人狂 會成為我們第一個目擊證人
Wake up, Mugalat, then you can tell us who did this to you.
醒醒，馬格來特 好告訴我們是誰幹的
Detective, I think that's enough.
探長，我看差不多了
Then you can tell us where you put Yakov Prosty's head.
好告訴我們你把 尤克·普羅斯蒂的頭藏哪了
43, 43, I need the around the clock security detail on a patient...
43小組，43小組 我需要對一個病人進行24小時全面監護
Magulat, M-A, gulat. At St. Luke's ICU.
馬格來特, 馬格——來特 在聖·盧卡斯急救中心
Is this the number I can call to report the case of police brutality?
這個電話是不是 可以舉報近期的警察連環殺人事件？
I can't get your tongue.
沒明白你什麼意思
Come out on bail again? Well, you think you can scare me, a little bitch, what you want?
又被保釋了？你以為你能嚇到我？ 小婊子，你想幹嘛？
Be careful, Detective, my taxes pay your salary.
注意點，探長 你的薪水裡有我納的稅
You don't pay any fucking taxes, you're only like a piece of shit.
你他媽還納過稅？ 你就一坨屎！
Go to the point, come on.
說正題，快點
One of your victims, Trager, stolen a whole lot guns down in south.
有名死者，叫特雷格 在城南偷了一批槍
Same guns turned up in your murder scenes.
所有的謀殺現場 都發現與此相同的槍
So it' simple. Find out who stolen the guns, you got your guy.
所以很簡單 查出誰偷了槍，就查出了兇手
So you know the guy?
這麼說你知道是誰？
Yeah, you know, there's a cop I'll deal who maybe a danger to the public.
要知道我面對的是個條子 對公眾可是個大威脅
I'm gonna live with myself, I just don't buy any saying.
我得多為自己想想 不能就這麼在電話裡講
Look, I'm gonna give two seconds more, give me a "Yes" or "No".
聽著，我再給你兩秒鐘 回答「是「或」否「
Do you know the guy? And when do I meet you to talk about it?
你知道不知道是誰？ 然後什麼時候我們可以面談？
- Firday, 9 pm, in my club. - I'll be there.
- 星期五，晚上9點，在我的夜總會 - 就這麼定了
It is dumb, dumb, this is the mother fucker dumbest right here,man.
愚蠢，愚蠢 這是最他媽愚蠢的事了
Easy son, easy, this is gonna be easy for you.
放鬆，小子，放鬆 你的任務很簡單
All you got to do is being bait, that's all. Be a little seduced for us, all right?
當個餌騙他上鉤，僅此而已 幫我們引蛇出洞，懂沒
You helped us, we got you covered.
你幫了我們 我們給你放行
You club doesn't get harassed all day. You don't have involved the door in and out of the jail.
你的夜總會再也不會整天被人騷擾 而你再也不用擔心進大牢
Do we have the deal or not?
你是干還是不幹？
Yeah, but your boy come in here and got Hannibal Lecter on my ass,
干，但你那個瘋狗來了之後 對我發飆
I don't know if Jody fucking Foster can come through the door.
我希望你們的人 能第一時間趕來「救駕」！
When the god dam ring called, man.
千萬別搞什麼亡羊補牢！
Evening, Detective, you want one?
晚上好，長官 想來杯嗎？
It's a shit, but it's better that nothing, right?
很難喝，但總比沒有強 對吧？
"As soon I heard that fucking Russian didn't die,"
「當我聽說那個鳥俄國佬沒死」
"I know things'll never be the same."
「我就知道大勢已去」
"I have to change the rules, the strategy."
「我必須得變規則，改策略」
"I have to be bold..., do something that could never be undone."
「我得大膽一些…， 幹點從沒幹過的事」
"I went for the unforgivable."
「我步入了不可饒恕之門」
Please, no...
求你了，不要…
Did you hear anything?! I just said!!
你沒聽見嗎！？ 我已經說了！
How exactly could I be blowing this out of proportion!?
這事我怎麼會 如此誇大其辭！？
That psychal just assaulted me!
那個變態 剛剛對我施暴！
I am telling he is a classic sociopath.
我可告訴你 他是典型的反社會分子！
Okay, okay, I'll look into it. All right? I'll look into it.
OK，OK，我會查的 行嗎？我會查的
Now, you stay the hell away from there. Understood? Understood?
現在，你馬上離開那裡 明白沒？明白沒？
Fuck that.
去他媽的
Excuse me, Ma'am, Detective Corelli, Let me see your reservation.
你好，女士，我是克萊利督察 我想看看你們酒店的預定記錄
Sure, help yourself.
當然，請自便
"Mc Daved Fisk"
"馬克·大衛·費斯克"
- Thank you. - Any time.
- 謝謝你 - 願意效勞
Yes, this is Detective Corelli.
是的，我是克萊利督察
I've been trying to reach Dectective Perez and Riley.
我想找佩雷斯和羅林探長
And I can't locate them.
但我聯繫不上他們
- I like to party - I like to cuddle and kiss.
- 我想開個慶功會 - 我想抱美人親美女
My tongue is hanging out, spitting fake blood.
我的舌頭耷拉著 噴著假血
I need to speak to them urgently.
我要馬上跟他們通話
Yes, I understand, but can I..., I need the location, please.
是，我明白，但是… 我必須知道他們的位置，拜託了
Hey, he's here.
嘿，他來了
Let me in.
讓我進去
Thank god, this is the police.
謝天謝地，總算見著警察了
- Yeah, so..., where do we go? - Follow me.
- 咱們這是要去哪？ - 跟我來吧
- Used to play ball coupla blocks from here. - What the fuck out there...
- 以前我還在幾條街外打過球 - 那邊亂七他媽八糟的
When I was a kid, I wasn't afraid of those guys like you.
我小的時候 根本不怕你這樣的人
Still ain't.
現在也沒怕啊
Now it's the Karen girl with me, it's a bad neighborhood.
現在凱倫闖入了我的生活 她可不是什麼友好鄰居
- Ain't bad for me. - Yeah.
- 我就喜歡這樣的 - 沒錯
Yeah, he's inside.
是的，他進去了
Well, so far so good.
目前來看一切正常
Stopped dallying the pleasant tree.
別扯閒篇了
- What you got for me? - Good, talk to him.
- 你手裡有什麼？ - 好極了，就這麼談
What do you think he's gonna do?
你猜他會怎麼著？
Oh, Christ, Lieutenant, this is a crack shit.
噢，別逗了，長官 他就是一混球
I lost three fucking teeth that day.
那天我掉了三顆牙
Well, he's not a civilian, he's fucking dealer.
他不是什麼「市民」 他就一毒品走私犯
So what? You guys love those stupid gold teeth. You should thank me.
那怎麼了？你們不就喜歡鑲金牙嘛 你還得謝我呢
Oh, he's wearing a vest. And Starsky and Hutch are watching him, like a couple of hawks.
他穿著防彈背心，斯塔斯基和哈金森正盯著他 就像一對鷹情侶
- Gay hawks. - Yeah, right there, buddy.
- 斷背之鷹 - 對，說對了，你個傢伙
All right, enough bullshit.
行了，廢話少說
So you know about our poetry boy, just talk to me. What you got for me?
你真的知道詩歌男？ 你有什麼證據？
- All right, here we go. - "Here we go."
- 來了，好戲開場了 - 「好戲開場」了
Would you please?
拜託，老兄！
Just caused the guy's talking tough, that don't mean a shit.
別看兩人聊的挺微妙 但不一定有鬼
Let me ask you something, Kopernik,
那我問你，羅卜頭
That gun in his belt..., What do you think? It's a service pistol?
他腰裡別的槍… 你以為是什麼？玩具槍啊？
I bet you it traces back to Trager, what do you think about that?
我敢打賭它就是從特雷格那來的 你敢不敢賭？
What do you want to bet?
你想賭什麼？
- Four hundred bucks. - You are on.
- 四百美金 - 成交
- I'm in for another five. - This is fun.
- 我再加五百 - 這下有意思了
- Look, I help you, you reciprocate. - So, help me.
- 聽著，我幫了你，你得付報酬 - 行，幫我吧
All right, in my loaded cell phone video, I got a recording of Trager the night you put him.
好吧，在我的手機裡 剛好有一段你幹掉特雷格那晚的記錄
- You got what? - I got a movie.
- 你說你有什麼？ - 我有段視頻記錄
Coupla kids back from the prom, reserving the special memories,
一群小孩跳舞回來 拍些畫面留做紀念
postive idea you Big Tom.
錄到的是湯姆大叔的臉
- Oh, yeah, me? - Yeah.
- 噢，真的？是我？ - 沒錯
Okay.
OK
- Now you know what I'm talking about. - Now I got it.
- 現在你明白我的意思了吧 - 現在我明白了
Yeah, well, so how do I look?
那麼，鏡頭裡的我怎麼樣？
Like a poet?
像個詩人？
- Because that's who I am, I'm a poet. - All right, come on, let's go.
- 因為那就是我嘛，我是詩人嘛 - 好了，是時候了，快行動
In fact, I've already wrote a poem for you, Spider. You want to hear it?
實際上，我還為你寫了首詩，蜘蛛 想聽聽嗎？
Drop your gun, right now! Father fucker, drop to ground!
放下槍，馬上！ 你他媽的，扔到地上！
- Right now! - Oh, grace me...
- 馬上！ - 噢，客氣點…
I mean nation will pay you two more or what?
政府又不會多付你錢
- Put the fuck weapon on the ground. - Gladly, gladly, right there.
- 把他媽槍放到地上！ - 願意，願意效勞，放那了
Right there.
就在那
- You wanna read my poem? - Easy, easy.
- 想看看我的詩嗎？ - 放鬆點，別緊張
There, read it.
拿去，讀讀吧
YOU TRIED TO SET ME UP, YOU FUCKS. AND THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT.
「爾等設計套我，一群飯桶」 「到頭來發現，兩手空空」
YOU THOUGHT I GET MY DICK CUT OFF, INSTEAD YOU WANT TO BLOW IT.
「想割我命根，達三番五次」 「未曾想自己，要為我吹簫」
- Great stuff.        - What is that shit? - Thank you.
- 好詩啊        - 什麼他媽玩意？ - 謝謝誇獎
That is poetry.
這才叫詩嘛
What are you doing here?
你來這幹嘛？
Don't look at me, partner. But I tagged along to protect your ass...
別看我，老搭檔 我跟著他們，是為了保護你
...and to see the look in their faces. It was worth it.
順便看看他們臉上那個表情 非常值得
Hey, we are doing our jobs, okay? I'm not gonna apologize.
我們全是為了工作，OK？ 我不會跟你道歉的
I don't want you to apologize, Teddy. There's killer out there with the badge.
我也不想聽你道歉，特裡 有人正別著警徽開槍殺人
What are you muddler doing here?
真不知道你兩個棒槌 跑這來幹嘛？
- What do you think we are doing here? - That's a good question.
- 你說我們來幹嘛？ - 這問題問得真好
- It's not him. - No, it's not him.
- 不是他 - 不，不是他
I just made a thousand bucks.
我剛剛贏了一千美金
Where is the..., where's the other gun? Come on. Give it to me. I know you got it.
在哪…，另一把槍在哪？ 快給我，我知道在你身上
Don't you frisk me, Sherlock, go ahead, frisk me.
幹嘛不搜我的身，神探 來啊，搜我啊
- Frisk me, go ahead. - I don't want to frisk you.
- 搜吧，放心 - 我不想搜你的身
Go ahead.
來吧
Nice touch, Mary. What are you doing after work?
手法不錯嘛，小妞 業餘時間都幹嘛啊？
Unless you're committed, I mean I don't wanna get in the middle of anything.
別怪我多嘴 我並不想干涉你的業餘生活
What happened to your face? your maid friend gave you a little love bite?
你臉怎麼了？ 你的女僕搭檔咬到了你臉上？
Shut the fuck up! Shut your fucking face!
閉他媽的嘴！ 去你他媽的什麼臉的！
I will blow your face! You mother fucker. Get the fuck away!...
我廢了你的臉！你媽的 快他媽離開這…
What's he talking about?
他說什麼？
What is he talking about is just 'cause you going for this does mean you're are not our guy.
他說的就是你雖然來了 但你卻不是我們要找的兇手
Now we need to break it down. Come on.
現在我們大家冷靜一下 拜託
- Don't let it just going fuck up. - Okay, he wants to fuck up...
- 別把事搞砸了 - 是他想搞砸的…
- Fuck your ass. - How about through it, man?
- 看你那屁眼 - 不如插一下試試，小妞！
- You made a mistake. - I'm gonna break this fuck down.
- 你給我記著！ - 我來處理後事
You fucking dog.
你媽個瘋狗
Relax, Spider. Come on, let's have a drink for it.
放鬆，蜘蛛 來，咱們喝兩杯
I saw what I think it's a refrigerator right here.
我記得這有個冰櫃
I'll be back in a second.
我馬上回來
Hey, pumpkinhead.
嗨，南瓜頭
Is this the person who shot you?
是不是這個人 開槍打的你？
Are you sure?
你確定？
No, you pumpkinhead.
不，你是南瓜頭
Did you miss me?
想我沒？
- Take it easy. - This okay, it's gonna be all right.
- 別緊張 - 沒事，沒什麼大不了的
- Jesus Christ, Rooster... - I just moved into the room. Yeah.
- 我的天，風凰… - 我只是進了這道門
Sit down.
坐下
Sit down!
坐下！
You get to know about this, Tom..., from me.
這個你應該知道，湯姆… 我得告訴你
Now, just open that little book. Start reading.
現在把筆記打開 讀出來
Everything you wanna know is in there.
你想知道的 都在那裡面
So, read.
所以，快讀吧
Out loud.
大點聲
For the record.
對著鏡頭
See little video here.
看到這攝像頭沒
My name is David Fisk,  Detective 1st Grade,
我叫大衛·費斯克，一級探長
I've been a cop in NYPD for nearly 30 years.
我在紐約警署當警察 已將近30年
- But, Dave, Dave,... - Yeah, what?
- 可是，大衛，大衛… - 怎麼了？
Tom, we got a lot to cover.
湯姆，我們有很事要做
And not much time to do it, so...
而且時間已經不多了，所以…
My name is David Fisk,  Detective 1st Grade,
我叫大衛·費斯克，一級探長
My name is David Fisk,
我叫大衛·費斯克
I've been a cop in NYPD for nearly 30 years.
我在紐約警署當警察 已將近30年
I don't expect you to remember me.
我不期望你還記得我
I mean it's been a long time, since you set me on your lap.
自從你將我攬入懷中 對我說你愛我
...told me you love me.
如今已過數十載
In that time...,
在這段時間裡…
I've killed fourteen people.
我殺了14個人
But I guarantee, ...
但我保證…
you will remember the name...
在你的餘生
for the rest of your life.
你將永遠記住這個名字
You don't become a cop because you want to serve or protect.
成為警察並非 為了服役亦或履行職責
You enjoy the force because they let you carry the gun and the badge.
崇尚強權，因為他可以讓你 槍與警微在握
Most people respect the badge, everybody respects the gun.
警徽讓很多人敬畏 而槍則能上每個人俯首
I'm the killer, I show up. I shot the door.
我是兇手，我現身了 我敲了門
What are you talking about?! This is not a fucking chess game!
你說什麼風涼話？ 這可不是什麼象棋比賽！
Who knows!? Maybe it is. You are making all the wrong moves.
誰知道呢？也許就是 這麼沉不氣呢
I'll put tools to his fucking head... myself.
我會打爛他的頭… 我親自
I know it to a moral certainty.
我百分之百的知道
Sort of getting numb to it, sort of getting numb to it...
有點麻木了 有點麻木了…
Tom Cowan, he was my role model.
湯姆·卡文，他是我的楷模
The day I stopped trying to be him, was the greatest day in my life.
我決定不再成為他的那一天 是我一生中最幸福的一天
Several years back, I framed a lowlife child killer, named Charles Randall.
幾年前，我陷害了一個 兒童殺人犯，叫查爾斯·蘭德爾
I should have known it will come back to haunt me.
我早該知道 我會為此付出代價
What,.., what do you want me to do with this?
你，你想讓我怎麼處置這個？
Is that all you got to say?
你就沒點別的要說？
I owe you this explation, pal.
我欠你一個說法，兄弟
Why are you telling me now?
那你幹嘛現在告訴我？
Ivan The Terrible, he's gonna wake up pretty soon.
那個恐怖俄國佬 他很快就會醒了
And he's gonna ID me.
他會指證我
Evening, Detective, you want one?
晚上好，長官 想來一杯嗎？
It's a shit, but it's better than nothing, right?
是很難喝，但總比沒有強，對吧
I can just walk right in here, your Prosky is asleep. Step outside, come on.
我就站這看看 你的病號睡著呢，出去，快點
Did I have a pick the wrong fuck Russian to shoot.
是不是我選錯了 這個鳥俄國佬了？
Now we're going off the record.
從現在起 就沒有錄像記錄了
Ah..., I want to take the rap for the Randall gun think. You saw that.
我想把蘭德爾的事替你扛下來 你也看到了
I mean considering the circumstance, why not? No need to thank me.
想想現在這情形，幹嘛不呢？ 不用謝我
- So this is about not being me? - Yeah.
- 就是說你想幫我背黑鍋？ - 正是
I don't get that.
我沒明白
You are great cop, Tom.
你是個好警察，湯姆
I mean you are the one I respire to all my life, it could never be.
你曾經是我一生中 最仰幕的一名警察
Then you broke the law.
可後來你破了戒
Planted the gun..., on Randall...,
槍支栽贓，嫁禍給蘭德爾
...let me down.
我被拖下了水
I lost my faith.
我丟了信仰
That's when all started.
一切就是從那時開始的
And once you did..., I couldn't stop.
而一旦我上了船 就沒法回頭了
Finally..., I didn't want to.
到最後，是我不想回頭了
So, I did my own thing, you know what? In the end?
所以，我就用自己的方式 你猜最後怎麼的？
It got done. The scums down.
事情解決了 惡人被除了
Then that's it, that's that.
就是這樣 就這樣了
I don't understand what you said,
我不太明白你的話
- don't understand any words... - I know you don't, Tom.
- 一個字都不懂 - 我知道你不懂，湯姆
As soon as I heard the Russian didn't die,
當我一聽說俄國佬沒有死
I knew I had to change the rules, do something that could never be undone.
我就知道我得改變遊戲規則了 幹些從未幹過的事
I went for the unforgivable.
我步入了不可饒恕之門
So what am I gonna do? My friend, partner, arrest you?
那我得怎麼辦？ 老朋友，老搭檔，逮捕你？
Some point I gotta call them in.
我本應該報警的
- We are team. - We were.
- 我們是好搭檔 - 曾經是
Yeah, we were.
是的，曾經是
- Great team. - That was yesterday, Dave.
- 很好的搭檔 - 那是昨的事的，大衛
Today, ...
今天…
Today you pointed a gun at me.
今天你把槍口對準了我
Blasting gone off yet.
已經加了保險了
- Bye, Tom. - Where are you going?
- 再見，湯姆 - 你要去哪？
I don't know, to hell, I suppose.
不知道，下地獄吧，也許
Hey, Dave.
嘿，大衛
Don't come loser!
別再靠近過來！
- You wouldn't. - You want to bet your life on it?
- 你不會的 - 你想拿命賭一把？
Come on, partner. I know you, you wouldn't.
別這樣，夥計 我瞭解你，你不會的
But I would.
但是我會！
Karen, just take it easy.
凱倫，別激動
- Can I get out of your mind. - Shut up, Dave.
- 我是不是讓你沒法安寧了 - 別說了，大衛
You..., you're gonna defand this...
你，你想幫這個…
...lowlife piece of shit!?
這個下流的混蛋？
- Oh, I am in your head... - I'm not defanding him.
- 噢，我把根紮在你腦裡了… - 我這不是幫他
- Just take it easy. - Fuck you, Turk. Put the gun down fast.
- 你別那麼激動 - 去你媽的，頑童！快把槍放下
- And if I don't? - Dave.
- 如果我不放呢 - 大衛
How about I blow your brain down.
那我就讓你腦袋開花
Don't move.
別動！
- Karen. - You blow me away, Turk dies.
- 凱倫. - 你開槍射我，頑童也跟著送命
- Is that your idea? - I said, don't move, you crap.
- 這就是你想要的？ - 我說了，別動！你個混蛋
Give me the gun, give me the gun.
把槍給我，把槍給我
Stay here.
呆著別動
Oh, man!
噢，拜託
Fuck!
他媽的！
These old locks.
全他媽的鎖死了
- I mean that ain't good. - Dave, we gotta end this thing.
- 這可不太好 - 大衛，咱們得把事了結了
- End it? - Put the gun down.
- 了結？ - 把槍放下
What's your plan? You're gonna arrest me?
你想幹嘛？ 逮捕我？
You're gonna take me down to prison, book me, fingerprint me.
關大牢？做筆錄？錄指紋？
Body care me, search me? What the fuck are you going to do?
搜我的身？ 你他媽的能幹嘛？
Roam me out of Heraldo, show "Freak" a week? Or better yet...
帶我到「荷拉都」遊街一周？ 讓公眾看看我這個怪物？
"Depth Psychol Profile" on Oprah...,
還是讓我上「歐普拉」的節目 來個「深度心理分析」？
Are you ready for that? I ain't gonna fly, man.
你有這個準備嗎？ 我現在是插翅難飛了
Dave, you gave me no choice.
大衛，你這是讓我沒的選啊
You got a choice, I escape.
你有的選，讓我逃掉
Would you do that for me, Tom?
你會嗎？湯姆？
- Would you let me escape? - Come on, don't do this.
- 你會讓我逃掉嗎？ - 別這樣，別逼我
I'm gonna make a run for it. What do you think?
我想試一試 怎麼樣？
You gotta do the right thing.
你得做個正確的選擇
That's 10-10, partner. Shots firing. Suspect's fleeing.
這是10-10，老搭檔 有人開槍，疑犯拒捕
- Let's go! - Come on, don't go in there.
- 來啊！ - 別這樣，別再錯下去了
Hey, partner, come on! Shots firing.
嘿，老搭檔，來啊！ 有人開槍了
- Don't do this. - Suspect fleeing. Resisting arrest?
- 別這樣 - 疑犯潛逃，想要拒捕？
Come on!
來啊！
A RIGHTEOUS MAN..., BEFORE ME STANDS.
「一位俠士，佇位於我面前」
A HERO IN THESE FILTHY LANDS.
「一位英雄，目睹那罪惡蔓延」
A BROTHER IN ARMS IN HEART ARE YOU.
「一位兄弟，與我心心相聯」
I was really hoping you get it too.
我真希望你也能明白
I do get it.
我明白
- No, you don't. - No, I get it.
- 不，你不明白 - 不，我明白
You know the only thing in this life...
知道嗎，這一生中只有一件事…
having given me any satisfaction...
能讓我得到滿足
was killing those fucks.
就是殺死那些混蛋
So this is for real.
看來真要走這一步了
I mean..., this one is bad.
我是說 這一步可不太好
10-13, officer down.
10-13，警員中槍
I ain't go anywhere, Tom. Ain't go anywhere.
我哪也不去，湯姆 哪也不去
It's okay.
沒事的
34 squad to central, 34 squad to central.
34小組呼叫總部
10-13, officer down. 184 St. Niklaas Officer down, 10-13. Hurry, huryy...
10-13，警員中槍，聖·尼克拉斯184號 警員中槍，快，快，快…
- 10-4, confirm called, 184 St. Niklaas, officer down. - Tom, don't.
- 收到指令，「聖·尼克拉斯 184號，警員中槍」 - 湯姆，不要
ETA six minutes.
救護人員約六分鐘到達
Don't,...
不要…
- 34 squad to central. - Central, go ahead, 34 squad.
- 34小組呼叫總部 - 這是總部，收到請講
- It's a 10-55, cancle the ambulance. - 10-5?
- 是10-55，人員微傷，取消救護車
Cancle the ambulance, 10-55, cancle the ambulance.
取消救護車 是10-55，人員微傷，取消救護車
- Are you sure on that? - Sure on that.
- 你確定嗎？ - 確定
- You did this show. - I know, partner. I know.
- 一直以來，你都很棒 - 我知道，老搭檔，我知道
We did good, Tom.
我們很棒，湯姆
Tom.
湯姆.
Tell me.
說給我聽
We did good, we did good.
我們很棒，我們很棒
You're a good man, Tom.
你是個好人，湯姆
You're a good man.
你是個好人
I wish you...
我祝願你…
magnificant successful.
有朝一日，功成名就
- Some piece of work, your partner. - Ligths.
- 你的搭檔還真變態 - 開燈
Look, Cowan, as we see it, Detective Fisk just closed the door on the poetry boy.
卡文，依我們看 詩歌男案已經同費斯克警探一起入土了
Good, whatever..., whatever you say.
好吧，隨便… 隨便你怎麼說
- Have we done? - Yeah, we done.
- 完事了嗎？ - 是的，完事了
My daughter called, she was upset about Rooster, and worried about me.
我女兒來電話了，她為風凰傷心 為我擔心
She asked me if I was like him to do something stupid.
她問我是不是我跟他一樣 會做傻事
Then I said, "like what?".
我說「比如什麼？」
Take anger management classes? Or retire?
對不公待遇大發雷霆？還是退休？
I said I was gonna do the same old thing I always do.
我說：我還是做我以前做的事
She said "good", whatelse could you do.
她說「很好」 不然你還能做什麼
I said "right, a real chip off the old block, my daughter".
我說：對啊，子肖其父嘛
She said that I was a cop, and a good one.
她還說我是名警察 一名好警察
Funny, Rooster said the same thing.
真諷刺，風凰也這麼說過
Hey, guys, let's really play ball.
嘿，姑娘們 來場比賽吧
Count to three...
數到三…
Everyone in?
都齊了嗎？
One, two, three. Yes!
一，二，三 開始！